<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cambodia - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/cambodia/feed/?simply_static_page=124745" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/cambodia/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 22:50:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cambodia - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/cambodia/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 19:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Updated June 2023: This post has been updated to provide the most current information and tips for an unforgettable adventure cycling Angkor Wat. Enjoy your journey! Embarking on a journey to Angkor Wat, the largest religious monument in the world, is an experience of a lifetime. Nestled in the heart of Cambodia, this UNESCO World [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/">An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="group w-full text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="flex p-4 gap-4 text-base md:gap-6 md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-[38rem] xl:max-w-3xl md:py-6 lg:px-0 m-auto">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p><strong>Updated June 2023</strong>: This post has been updated to provide the most current information and tips for an unforgettable adventure cycling Angkor Wat. Enjoy your journey!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Embarking on a journey to Angkor Wat, the largest religious monument in the world, is an experience of a lifetime. Nestled in the heart of Cambodia, this UNESCO World Heritage Site is a testament to the grandeur of the Khmer Empire that once ruled these lands. And what better way to explore this ancient city than by cycling Angkor Wat? This article will guide you through our adventure, providing tips and insights to help you plan your own.</p>
<h2>The Journey Begings</h2>
<p>Our adventure began in Siem Reap, a city that serves as the gateway to the Angkor region. After a long journey from Thailand, we were ready to explore the wonders of Angkor Park. The anticipation was high, and we were a bit apprehensive that the experience might not live up to our expectations. But as we soon discovered, Angkor Wat is a must-visit for every true traveler. If you&#8217;re a temple enthusiast, you&#8217;ll simply fall in love with it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-563 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg" alt="Rafa in Angkor Wat" width="392" height="588" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-200x300.jpg 200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Getting there</strong></h2>
<p>Reaching Angkor Park from Siem Reap is straightforward. You can either fly directly to Siem Reap or <a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">cross the Thai-Cambodian border</a> if you&#8217;re coming from Thailand, like we did. Alternatively, you can also travel from Vietnam. Once in Siem Reap, the journey to Angkor Park is a short one, with the distance being about 7 km.</p>
<h2><strong>How much is it?</strong></h2>
<p>Siem Reap is an affordable city, with meals costing around $3. Accommodation is also reasonably priced. We stayed at <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.es.html?aid=304142&amp;group_adults=1&amp;label=gen173nr-1BCAsoeEIYdmVsa29tbWVuLWJvdXRpcXVlLXZpbGxhSDNYBGhGiAEBmAEKuAEHyAEM2AEB6AEBiAIBqAIDuAK7052kBsACAdICJDhhMzIwNDZiLWM0MjQtNDJjMy05OGQwLTUxYzZhNjRlZTgzY9gCBeACAQ-Share-C4h0xWo%401686596043&amp;no_rooms=1">Villa D Riverside Boutique Hotel</a>, which cost around $10 per night. The guesthouse was top-notch, with great staff, cleanliness, and a small swimming pool. It also provided bikes, which we used for our adventure.</p>
<p>However, the entry to Angkor Park is quite pricey. You have three options: a one-day pass for $37, a three-day pass for $62, or a seven-day pass for $72. We opted for the three-day pass, which was sufficient for our exploration.</p>
<h2>Cycling Angkor Wat: The Adventure</h2>
<p>Most visitors hire a Tuk Tuk to explore the park. But we decided that cycling Angkor Wat was the way to go, at least for the first day. It allowed us to be active and truly immerse ourselves in the experience. However, be prepared for the heat. Angkor is a hot place, so it&#8217;s best to start the day very early and retire early.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-542 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="3500" height="2800" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg 3500w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-300x240.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-768x614.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-1024x819.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3500px) 100vw, 3500px" /></p>
<h2>Our First Day: The Big Circuit</h2>
<p>Our first day was dedicated to the big circuit. The alarm rang at 4:30 AM. Equipped with our lanterns, we cycled to Angkor Park. The anticipation was high as we pedaled through the quiet streets of Siem Reap, the cool morning air providing a refreshing start to our adventure.</p>
<p>We passed by Angkor Wat, which was already bustling with tourists waiting for the sunrise. However, we decided to stick to our plan and cycled a bit more. Ten minutes later, we arrived at Bayon, one of the biggest temples in the park. We were just in time for the sunrise, and it was well worth it. We had the temple just for ourselves, sharing the serene atmosphere only with a dog and a monk on his early walk.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-551 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg" alt="Angkor Wat sunrise" width="2200" height="1467" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg 2200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2200px) 100vw, 2200px" /></p>
<p>From Bayon, we embarked on the big circuit. This route covers many temples, including Preah Khan, Neak Pean, and Ta Som. Each temple had its own unique charm, from the intricate carvings of Preah Khan to the serene waters surrounding Neak Pean. Ta Som, with its iconic tree growing out of the eastern entrance, was a sight to behold.</p>
<p>Cycling around Angkor Park was more exhausting than we had anticipated. The heat, combined with the distance, made it a challenging endeavor. But the sense of discovery and the beauty of the temples made it all worthwhile. By 1 PM, we were a bit templed out and decided to call it a day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-548 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg" alt="Temples" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg 3000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></p>
<p>The ride back home was rewarding. We were greeted by a family of monkeys on the road, a delightful end to our adventure. Despite the exhaustion, the sense of accomplishment was overwhelming. We had cycled around Angkor Park, exploring its ancient temples and immersing ourselves in its rich history.</p>
<p>Time to come back to the hotel and hit the pool!</p>
<h2>Our Second Day: The Small Circuit</h2>
<p>After the exertion of the previous day, we decided to give our legs a rest and hired a TukTuk for our second day of exploration. Our driver, Dada, was a friendly local who helped us plan our day and shared interesting insights about the temples and the local culture.</p>
<p>We started our day with a visit to Angkor Wat. Even though we didn&#8217;t catch the sunrise, the temple was still a sight to behold in the early morning light. We spent a good two hours exploring the temple, marveling at its intricate carvings and grand architecture.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-561 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg" alt="A monk in Angkor Wat" width="2734" height="1864" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg 2734w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-300x205.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-768x524.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-1024x698.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2734px) 100vw, 2734px" /></p>
<p>Next, Dada took us to Banteay Samre, a temple located deep in the countryside. The journey to the temple was an adventure in itself. We passed through rural landscapes, witnessing the simple life of Cambodian families living in the countryside. Along the way, we stopped to learn about palm oil production and even got to taste some sweets made from it.</p>
<p>After our visit to Banteay Samre, we returned to our hotel for a well-deserved lunch and a short nap. Refreshed and recharged, we set off in the afternoon to continue our exploration of the small circuit.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-541 size-full aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg" alt="Tomb Raider" width="1795" height="1346" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg 1795w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-300x225.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-768x576.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1795px) 100vw, 1795px" /></p>
<p>The highlight of the afternoon was our visit to Ta Prohm, also known as the &#8220;Tomb Raider&#8221; temple. With its overgrown trees and moss-covered stones, Ta Prohm had a unique charm that made us feel like we were on an adventure movie set.</p>
<p>We ended the day trying to catch the sunset at Phnom Bakheng, a popular viewpoint. However, due to the limit on the number of visitors, we couldn&#8217;t make it to the top. Instead, we enjoyed a peaceful sunset at Angkor Wat, which was less crowded and offered beautiful photo opportunities.</p>
<p>In conclusion, our second day of cycling Angkor Wat was a blend of adventure, culture, and history. Despite the heat and exhaustion, the beauty of the temples and the charm of the countryside made it a day to remember. Whether you choose to cycle or hire a TukTuk, exploring the small circuit of Angkor Wat is an experience you won&#8217;t want to miss.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<div class="group w-full text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 dark:bg-gray-800">
<div class="flex p-4 gap-4 text-base md:gap-6 md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-[38rem] xl:max-w-3xl md:py-6 lg:px-0 m-auto">
<div class="flex-shrink-0 flex flex-col relative items-end">
<div class="w-[30px]">
<div class="relative flex">
<p>Cycling Angkor Wat is an unforgettable experience. It allows you to explore the ancient city at your own pace, taking in the sights, sounds, and smells that make this place so unique. Whether you&#8217;re a history buff, an adventure seeker, or a casual traveler, cycling Angkor Wat is an adventure you don&#8217;t want to miss.</p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">How to survive crossing Thai-Cambodian border</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Enjoyed the article? We provide our content free and without the use of affiliates, this is how you know we&#8217;re authentic. If you&#8217;d like to support us to continue doing this, consider buying us a coffee!<script src="https://cdnjs.buymeacoffee.com/1.0.0/button.prod.min.js" type="text/javascript" data-name="bmc-button" data-slug="itfeelsgoodtobelost" data-color="#13d5d8" data-emoji="" data-font="Cookie" data-text="Buy me a coffee" data-outline-color="#000000" data-font-color="#000000" data-coffee-color="#FFDD00"></script></em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-540 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg" alt="Sunset in Angkor Wat" width="3300" height="2200" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg 3300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3300px) 100vw, 3300px" /></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-761 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="647" height="364" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png 560w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 647px) 100vw, 647px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/">An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 07:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called Poipet, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called <strong>Poipet</strong>, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, but I&#8217;ll share our experience.</p>
<p><strong>Spoiler alert: It wasn&#8217;t as bad as they say it is!</strong></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Before crossing the Cambodian border</h2>
<p>We were in <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/" data-wplink-url-error="true"><strong>Koh Chang</strong></a>, an island on the Gulf of Thailand. We decided to travel to Cambodia, due to its proximity and to visit <strong>Angkor Wat</strong>, one of the most amazing monuments in the world.</p>
<p>While In Ko Chang, we stayed at <a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><strong>Little Eden Bungalows</strong></a>, a beautiful backpackers bungalow resort, where we were offered transportation to Siem Reap (the city where Angkor Wat is) through an external Thai company. The receptionist recommended not do the whole trip with them and get a taxi as soon as we reached Cambodia. This way we would avoid scams like: &#8220;Sorry the bus is broken, you all need to get these expensive taxis waiting conveniently for you in this corner&#8221;.</p>
<p>We had also read online to not even complete the whole trip in Thai side with them. They would do a stop before crossing the Cambodian border in a restaurant a few kilometres away, collecting everyone&#8217;s passports and forcing you to get the Cambodian visa through an unofficial office where you end up paying up to two times more!</p>
<p>The list of scams goes on and on, but we still decided to go for it. It was much cheaper and comfortable than coming all the way back to Bangkok and fly to Siem Reap.</p>
<p><strong>TIP: Don&#8217;t overread online about crossing the Cambodian border. </strong>YES, you need to do to make sure you read a bit to have everything under control. Once you&#8217;ve done that, stop reading. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll be like me; worried to death the night before and asking yourself why on earth you would do something like that. IT WILL BE OK <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<h2>The CROSSING day</h2>
<p>In the morning, a mini-van picked us up at 7 AM. The guy didn&#8217;t seem very friendly, but who cares, right? After picking up some tourists we made it to the pier, where we waited 30 minutes for the ferry. 45 minutes later we had made it to the mainland.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-191 size-full" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/koh-chang101.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: ready!" width="6000" height="4000" /></p>
<p>Back in the mini-van, we had a 3 hours drive ahead of us to <strong>Aranyaprathet</strong>, the Thai town where the border is. Turned up the stories were right and the guys took us to a restaurant where we &#8220;<em>would have lunch before going to the visa office</em>&#8220;. We said <em>&#8220;nope, thank you, we&#8217;ll walk&#8221;,</em> got our luggage and started walking. We had read they could get pushy when doing this but they were totally ok with it.</p>
<p>At this point, it was recommended to get a Tuk Tuk to the border, as the town is supposed to be dangerous. We didn&#8217;t see any (plus they would try to take us to the &#8220;unofficial office&#8221; to scam us), so we just walked. The town wasn&#8217;t <em>nice</em> but it didn&#8217;t feel dangerous either. Thai people taking care of their business and not a single person said anything to us. After 15 minutes we made it to the border. Happy times!</p>
<p>We were expecting long queues but it was clear we were way ahead than most of the tourists, which were probably stuck &#8220;having lunch&#8221;. In less than 10-15 minutes we had our leaving stamp in the passport and we were in Poipet, Cambodia.</p>
<p>Once there, some guys tried to help us out with our transport to Siem Reap as they &#8220;knew someone who could take us very cheap&#8221;. After ignoring them, we walked to the Visa Cambodian office where we would get our visa. Funny enough, we found again an empty office, full of Cambodian officers (around 10) and maybe 3-4 tourists. We filled up the requested documents, handed it to the officers along with a photo and&#8230;it was scam time again!</p>
<p><strong>The visa price is officially 30$</strong>, and even in the office, there is a big sign that says the same thing, 30$. We had read they would ask for more money and turned out to be right. The officer pointed to a very lame paper where we could read: <em>&#8220;30$ + 100 Baths&#8221;</em> (Bath is the Thai currency, 100 baths are about 3$). We said <em>&#8220;nope, it&#8217;s only 30$, is written there&#8221;</em>, but the guy didn&#8217;t even blink and repeated &#8220;<em>100 Baths</em>&#8220;. We tried to make him understand but he left us no choice, so we gave him the 100 baths.</p>
<blockquote><p>Trying to avoid the scam wasn&#8217;t really about the money but about playing by the book. Unfortunately, we didn&#8217;t have enough patience. If you hand out the 30$, sit and wait, after some time they will give you the visa. Who knows how long you will wait though.</p></blockquote>
<p>We walked a bit more and pass around a few casinos where Thai people gamble as it&#8217;s illegal in Thailand. Next step was to get the Cambodia entering stamp in our passport, which went quite smoothly. A random guy offered me a pen and of course, it turned out he knew a guy that would take us very cheap to Siem Reap. We got our stamps in our passports, walked out of the office and the &#8220;pen guy&#8221; was waiting for us. He offered a price of 45$ to <em>our hotel </em>(we were 3, as Nicky, an American friend we had met in Koh Chang, had joined us). After negotiating a bit, we agreed on 40$ (13$ each) and we were on our way to Siem Reap.</p>
<h2>Crossing the Cambodian border: CHECKED!</h2>
<p>So far so good! But we knew it wasn&#8217;t over yet. Turns out you can&#8217;t really trust these guys at all. He didn&#8217;t take us to our hotels, but to a random place in the city where a guy in his Tuk Tuk came to pick us up. He would only take us for free if we hired him for the next day to visit Angkor Wat.</p>
<p>We said no and started to negotiate prices again. Our friend Nicky was staying in a different hostel, meaning the guy wasn&#8217;t happy about doing 2 stops. He wanted us to pay 5$ each to take us to the hostels (15$ in total), but we said we would take another Tuk Tuk and he finally settled in 10$. We would later find out that was still very pricey, but at that moment we didn&#8217;t care. 15 minutes later,<strong> we made it to our hostel safe and sound</strong>!</p>
<p>Summing up, if you&#8217;re thinking about crossing the Cambodian border by land, <strong>don&#8217;t stress and do it</strong>, it&#8217;s fine! We left Koh Chang at 7 AM and arrived at our hostel in Siem Reap at 5 PM<strong>. </strong>I can&#8217;t say it was a pleasant journey but it wasn&#8217;t that bad and<strong> it turned out to be a bit of fun.</strong> It&#8217;s sad neither the Thai nor Cambodian governments care about tourists being scammed as soon as they enter their countries. This shouldn&#8217;t stop you from enjoying what really is a beautiful country with beautiful people!</p>
<h2><strong>Accommodation</strong></h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for accommodation, we stayed at <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Velkommen Guesthouse</a>.</strong> It was cheap, nice (swimming pool!) and well located as it&#8217;s closer to Angkor Wat than most of the hostels. They provide free bikes so you can cycle to the city centre (10 minutes) or to Angkor Wat! 100% recommended it!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-215" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: safe and sound :)" width="467" height="831" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg 1166w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-169x300.jpg 169w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-576x1024.jpg 576w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-07-30 09:58:42 by W3 Total Cache
-->