<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>backpacking Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/backpacking/feed/?simply_static_page=83109" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/backpacking/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:46:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>backpacking Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/backpacking/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 19:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angkor Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angkor wat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siem reap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Updated June 2023: This post has been updated to provide the most current information and tips for an unforgettable adventure cycling Angkor Wat. Enjoy your journey! Embarking on a journey to Angkor Wat, the largest religious monument in the world, is an experience of a lifetime. Nestled in the heart of Cambodia, this UNESCO World [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/">An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="group w-full text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 bg-gray-50 dark:bg-[#444654]">
<div class="flex p-4 gap-4 text-base md:gap-6 md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-[38rem] xl:max-w-3xl md:py-6 lg:px-0 m-auto">
<div class="relative flex w-[calc(100%-50px)] flex-col gap-1 md:gap-3 lg:w-[calc(100%-115px)]">
<div class="flex flex-grow flex-col gap-3">
<div class="min-h-[20px] flex flex-col items-start gap-4 whitespace-pre-wrap break-words">
<div class="markdown prose w-full break-words dark:prose-invert light">
<p><strong>Updated June 2023</strong>: This post has been updated to provide the most current information and tips for an unforgettable adventure cycling Angkor Wat. Enjoy your journey!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Embarking on a journey to Angkor Wat, the largest religious monument in the world, is an experience of a lifetime. Nestled in the heart of Cambodia, this UNESCO World Heritage Site is a testament to the grandeur of the Khmer Empire that once ruled these lands. And what better way to explore this ancient city than by cycling Angkor Wat? This article will guide you through our adventure, providing tips and insights to help you plan your own.</p>
<h2>The Journey Begings</h2>
<p>Our adventure began in Siem Reap, a city that serves as the gateway to the Angkor region. After a long journey from Thailand, we were ready to explore the wonders of Angkor Park. The anticipation was high, and we were a bit apprehensive that the experience might not live up to our expectations. But as we soon discovered, Angkor Wat is a must-visit for every true traveler. If you&#8217;re a temple enthusiast, you&#8217;ll simply fall in love with it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-563 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg" alt="Rafa in Angkor Wat" width="392" height="588" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-200x300.jpg 200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Getting there</strong></h2>
<p>Reaching Angkor Park from Siem Reap is straightforward. You can either fly directly to Siem Reap or <a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">cross the Thai-Cambodian border</a> if you&#8217;re coming from Thailand, like we did. Alternatively, you can also travel from Vietnam. Once in Siem Reap, the journey to Angkor Park is a short one, with the distance being about 7 km.</p>
<h2><strong>How much is it?</strong></h2>
<p>Siem Reap is an affordable city, with meals costing around $3. Accommodation is also reasonably priced. We stayed at <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.es.html?aid=304142&amp;group_adults=1&amp;label=gen173nr-1BCAsoeEIYdmVsa29tbWVuLWJvdXRpcXVlLXZpbGxhSDNYBGhGiAEBmAEKuAEHyAEM2AEB6AEBiAIBqAIDuAK7052kBsACAdICJDhhMzIwNDZiLWM0MjQtNDJjMy05OGQwLTUxYzZhNjRlZTgzY9gCBeACAQ-Share-C4h0xWo%401686596043&amp;no_rooms=1">Villa D Riverside Boutique Hotel</a>, which cost around $10 per night. The guesthouse was top-notch, with great staff, cleanliness, and a small swimming pool. It also provided bikes, which we used for our adventure.</p>
<p>However, the entry to Angkor Park is quite pricey. You have three options: a one-day pass for $37, a three-day pass for $62, or a seven-day pass for $72. We opted for the three-day pass, which was sufficient for our exploration.</p>
<h2>Cycling Angkor Wat: The Adventure</h2>
<p>Most visitors hire a Tuk Tuk to explore the park. But we decided that cycling Angkor Wat was the way to go, at least for the first day. It allowed us to be active and truly immerse ourselves in the experience. However, be prepared for the heat. Angkor is a hot place, so it&#8217;s best to start the day very early and retire early.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-542 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="3500" height="2800" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg 3500w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-300x240.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-768x614.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-1024x819.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3500px) 100vw, 3500px" /></p>
<h2>Our First Day: The Big Circuit</h2>
<p>Our first day was dedicated to the big circuit. The alarm rang at 4:30 AM. Equipped with our lanterns, we cycled to Angkor Park. The anticipation was high as we pedaled through the quiet streets of Siem Reap, the cool morning air providing a refreshing start to our adventure.</p>
<p>We passed by Angkor Wat, which was already bustling with tourists waiting for the sunrise. However, we decided to stick to our plan and cycled a bit more. Ten minutes later, we arrived at Bayon, one of the biggest temples in the park. We were just in time for the sunrise, and it was well worth it. We had the temple just for ourselves, sharing the serene atmosphere only with a dog and a monk on his early walk.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-551 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg" alt="Angkor Wat sunrise" width="2200" height="1467" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg 2200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2200px) 100vw, 2200px" /></p>
<p>From Bayon, we embarked on the big circuit. This route covers many temples, including Preah Khan, Neak Pean, and Ta Som. Each temple had its own unique charm, from the intricate carvings of Preah Khan to the serene waters surrounding Neak Pean. Ta Som, with its iconic tree growing out of the eastern entrance, was a sight to behold.</p>
<p>Cycling around Angkor Park was more exhausting than we had anticipated. The heat, combined with the distance, made it a challenging endeavor. But the sense of discovery and the beauty of the temples made it all worthwhile. By 1 PM, we were a bit templed out and decided to call it a day.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-548 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg" alt="Temples" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg 3000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></p>
<p>The ride back home was rewarding. We were greeted by a family of monkeys on the road, a delightful end to our adventure. Despite the exhaustion, the sense of accomplishment was overwhelming. We had cycled around Angkor Park, exploring its ancient temples and immersing ourselves in its rich history.</p>
<p>Time to come back to the hotel and hit the pool!</p>
<h2>Our Second Day: The Small Circuit</h2>
<p>After the exertion of the previous day, we decided to give our legs a rest and hired a TukTuk for our second day of exploration. Our driver, Dada, was a friendly local who helped us plan our day and shared interesting insights about the temples and the local culture.</p>
<p>We started our day with a visit to Angkor Wat. Even though we didn&#8217;t catch the sunrise, the temple was still a sight to behold in the early morning light. We spent a good two hours exploring the temple, marveling at its intricate carvings and grand architecture.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-561 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg" alt="A monk in Angkor Wat" width="2734" height="1864" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg 2734w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-300x205.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-768x524.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-1024x698.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2734px) 100vw, 2734px" /></p>
<p>Next, Dada took us to Banteay Samre, a temple located deep in the countryside. The journey to the temple was an adventure in itself. We passed through rural landscapes, witnessing the simple life of Cambodian families living in the countryside. Along the way, we stopped to learn about palm oil production and even got to taste some sweets made from it.</p>
<p>After our visit to Banteay Samre, we returned to our hotel for a well-deserved lunch and a short nap. Refreshed and recharged, we set off in the afternoon to continue our exploration of the small circuit.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-541 size-full aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg" alt="Tomb Raider" width="1795" height="1346" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg 1795w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-300x225.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-768x576.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1795px) 100vw, 1795px" /></p>
<p>The highlight of the afternoon was our visit to Ta Prohm, also known as the &#8220;Tomb Raider&#8221; temple. With its overgrown trees and moss-covered stones, Ta Prohm had a unique charm that made us feel like we were on an adventure movie set.</p>
<p>We ended the day trying to catch the sunset at Phnom Bakheng, a popular viewpoint. However, due to the limit on the number of visitors, we couldn&#8217;t make it to the top. Instead, we enjoyed a peaceful sunset at Angkor Wat, which was less crowded and offered beautiful photo opportunities.</p>
<p>In conclusion, our second day of cycling Angkor Wat was a blend of adventure, culture, and history. Despite the heat and exhaustion, the beauty of the temples and the charm of the countryside made it a day to remember. Whether you choose to cycle or hire a TukTuk, exploring the small circuit of Angkor Wat is an experience you won&#8217;t want to miss.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<div class="group w-full text-gray-800 dark:text-gray-100 border-b border-black/10 dark:border-gray-900/50 dark:bg-gray-800">
<div class="flex p-4 gap-4 text-base md:gap-6 md:max-w-2xl lg:max-w-[38rem] xl:max-w-3xl md:py-6 lg:px-0 m-auto">
<div class="flex-shrink-0 flex flex-col relative items-end">
<div class="w-[30px]">
<div class="relative flex">
<p>Cycling Angkor Wat is an unforgettable experience. It allows you to explore the ancient city at your own pace, taking in the sights, sounds, and smells that make this place so unique. Whether you&#8217;re a history buff, an adventure seeker, or a casual traveler, cycling Angkor Wat is an adventure you don&#8217;t want to miss.</p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">How to survive crossing Thai-Cambodian border</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-540 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg" alt="Sunset in Angkor Wat" width="3300" height="2200" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg 3300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3300px) 100vw, 3300px" /></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-761 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="647" height="364" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png 560w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 647px) 100vw, 647px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/">An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bang Bao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klong Koi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh chang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koh Kut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koh Mak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lonely Beach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Note: This post was last updated on June 2023 to include the most current information and recommendations. If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note</strong>: This post was last updated on <strong>June 2023</strong> to include the most current information and recommendations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce competition, there are compelling reasons to believe that Koh Chang is one of the best islands in Thailand.</p>
<h2><strong>Getting to Koh Chang</strong></h2>
<p>Getting to Koh Chang might be a bit tricky as there&#8217;s no airport on the island. You can either fly to Trat&#8217;s airport from Bangkok and then take a taxi to Ao Thammachat&#8217;s port, where you can reach Koh Chang by sea in 30 minutes. Alternatively, you can take a bus from Ekkamai&#8217;s bus station in Bangkok, which takes around six hours (but is very comfortable!), and then catch a boat.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;re on the island, you can get around by taxi or by renting a motorbike. <strong>Exploring Koh Chang on a motorbike is one of our favorite memories from our trips around the world</strong>. It&#8217;s the best and cheapest option if you know how to drive.</p>
<p>Now, let&#8217;s dive into the best things to do in Koh Chang.</p>
<h2><strong>What to do</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>Klong Koi Beach</strong></h4>
<p>This beach is a paradise. The sand is amazing, and the water is surprisingly warm. On your way, visit Bang Bao Pier, where you can have a smoothie and do some shopping in the shops on the pier.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-184 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg" alt="koh chang " width="640" height="776" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg 845w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-248x300.jpg 248w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-768x931.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1267x1536.jpg 1267w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1690x2048.jpg 1690w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<h4><strong>Lonely Beach</strong></h4>
<p>While the beach in Lonely Beach is nothing special, the area is great for enjoying food or having some drinks. The atmosphere is very chilled during the day, although it can get a bit lively at night with some parties going on. Lonely Beach is also a great spot to enjoy sunrises. We enjoyed an awesome one at <a href="https://www.agoda.com/es-es/warapura-resort/hotel/koh-chang-th.html?finalPriceView=2&amp;isShowMobileAppPrice=false&amp;cid=1763310&amp;numberOfBedrooms=&amp;familyMode=false&amp;adults=2&amp;children=0&amp;rooms=1&amp;maxRooms=0&amp;checkIn=2023-06-12&amp;isCalendarCallout=false&amp;childAges=&amp;numberOfGuest=0&amp;missingChildAges=false&amp;travellerType=-1&amp;showReviewSubmissionEntry=false&amp;currencyCode=EUR&amp;isFreeOccSearch=false&amp;tag=3ca4e5ca-12bf-3f82-a5b3-51dd334b432a&amp;isCityHaveAsq=false&amp;los=1&amp;searchrequestid=d3196397-4a4e-4057-a418-7c2e442572b1">Warapura Resort</a>, which has happy hours in the early evening, making it the perfect spot to see the sunset.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-171 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-sunset-e1582292527691.jpg" alt="koh chang sunset" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<h4>Best Beaches in Koh Chang: White Sand, Khlong Prao, and Kai Bae</h4>
<p>These three beaches are some of the best places to visit in Koh Chang. White Sand Beach is the most popular and busiest beach on the island. It&#8217;s a great place to relax, swim, and enjoy the sun. There are plenty of restaurants and bars nearby, making it a lively place to spend the day.</p>
<p>Khlong Prao Beach is a bit quieter but equally beautiful. It&#8217;s a long, sandy beach that&#8217;s perfect for long walks and sunbathing. The beach is lined with coconut trees, adding to its tropical charm. There are also several resorts and restaurants nearby.</p>
<p>Kai Bae Beach is a hidden gem. It&#8217;s less crowded than the other two beaches, making it a great place to relax and enjoy the tranquility. The beach is surrounded by lush greenery, creating a serene and peaceful atmosphere.</p>
<h4>Exploring Khlong Phlu Waterfall: A Must-Do in Koh Chang</h4>
<p>If you get tired of beaches, you can go to Khlong Phlu, where you can have a nice short trek and enjoy sunbathing by a waterfall. You can dive in if you don&#8217;t mind the company of the small-medium fish!</p>
<p>Remember to wear sturdy shoes for the hike and bring some insect repellent to protect yourself from mosquitoes. There&#8217;s a small entrance fee to the national park, but it&#8217;s well worth it for the chance to see this beautiful waterfall.</p>
<h2>Accommodation</h2>
<h4><strong>Budget option: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.es.html">Little Eden Bungalows</a></strong></h4>
<p>For budget travelers, Little Eden Bungalows is a great option. Located in Lonely Beach, there are about 10 small bungalows. They also rent motorbikes for a good price (300 bahts).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-187 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg" alt="little eden" width="640" height="563" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg 1024w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-300x264.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-768x675.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1536x1349.jpg 1536w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-2048x1799.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>Comfort option</strong>: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.es.html">Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort</a></h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a bit more comfort, Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort is an excellent choice. With its excellent location, amazing pool, live music, delicious breakfast, and great sunsets, it&#8217;s an outstanding resort.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.en.html?aid=1593090&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=2"><img decoding="async" class="size-full aligncenter" src="https://q-cf.bstatic.com/images/hotel/max1280x900/162/162915342.jpg" width="1280" height="853" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>Embrace the Adventure</strong></h2>
<p>Remember, Koh Chang is one of those places where you don’t really need to worry about what to do. Just ride a motorbike and GET LOST. You can also visit Koh Mak and Koh Kut, the other islands in the archipelago. We&#8217;ve heard great things about them, but they are a bit far, so if you go, make sure you get some accommodation to spend the night and make the most of them.</p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">How to survive crossing Thai-Cambodian border</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/" rel="bookmark" data-wplink-url-error="true">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koh Samet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paradise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stay samet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Updated in 2023: This post has been updated to ensure it contains the most accurate and comprehensive guide for exploring Koh Samet. Enjoy planning your adventure! Embarking on an adventure exploring Koh Samet, a lovely island nestled in the Gulf of Thailand, is a perfect escape from the bustling city of Bangkok. This comprehensive travel [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/">Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i><strong>U</strong><b>pdated in 2023</b>: This post has been updated to ensure it contains the most accurate and comprehensive guide for exploring Koh Samet. Enjoy planning your adventure!</i></p>
<p>Embarking on an adventure exploring Koh Samet, a lovely island nestled in the Gulf of Thailand, is a perfect escape from the bustling city of Bangkok. This comprehensive travel guide will help you navigate through the island&#8217;s pristine beaches, amazing sunsets, and vibrant nightlife. Koh Samet is still a hidden gem, so make sure you explore this paradise before it becomes another crowded island!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you are like us and made the mistake to spend some days in Pattaya&nbsp;you&#8217;ll find exploring Koh Samet a refreshing experience.<span id="more-68"></span></p>
<h3><strong>How to get there?</strong></h3>
<p>We went to Koh Samet from Pattaya. If you&#8217;re going from Bangkok, I&#8217;d expect there are buses from Ekkamai bus station to Ban Phe port. Worst scenario, you could easily go to Pattaya and then go to Ban Phe. This is how we did it from Pattaya:</p>
<ol>
<li>Go to this <strong style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );"><a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Praew+Souvenir+@Tesco+Lotus+Central+Pattaya/@12.9337661,100.9025029,18z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x3102be1c9a4d3ec5:0xade9af5b32c85c66!2sPattaya+Bus+station!8m2!3d12.9499477!4d100.9033208!3m4!1s0x310295f03b6ec8e3:0x26063f5fe5264481!8m2!3d12.9337639!4d100.9034285">location</a></strong>. In front of the Tesco Lotus, there is a <b style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );">small travel office that organizes trips by van.</b></li>
<li>Tell them you want to go to <strong>Ban-Phe port</strong> to then go to Koh Samet<b>.</b> The trip takes an hour and it costs 300 bahts (2 people).</li>
<li>Once in the port, walk to the ticket office. There are slow and fast boats. We took a fast boat, which after haggling a bit, cost us 250 bahts (2 people).</li>
<li>A short 15-minute ride later, you&#8217;ll arrive at Koh Samet. A coast guard will approach you to collect the national park fee, which is 200 baht. Rest assured, exploring Koh Samet is worth every penny!</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180318_144359-e1570995593904.jpg" alt="Ban Phe port" width="3120" height="2085"></p>
<h3><strong>How to move around</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">The island is fairly small, but you&#8217;ll need transport to move around. Options are:</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hopping in big taxis that move around the island all day.</strong> The price depends on where you&#8217;re going but keep in mind they&#8217;re generally pricey.</li>
<li><strong>Rent a bike and cycle around!</strong> Ecological and cheap.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;"><strong>Our favorite: hire a motorbike </strong>(250 bahts per day). Only for those who know how to drive. If you&#8217;re a beginner, you should be fine as it is quite easy to drive in Koh Samet. Drive safely!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>A few things to convince you why exploring Koh Samet is worth it</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hat Sai Kaew Beach</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">The most popular beach. During the day expect a lot of people, towels, activities like snorkeling and so on.&nbsp; In the night the atmosphere is stunning: nice restaurants, fire shows, relaxed parties, locals hanging out&#8230;</p>
<h3><img decoding="async" style="font-size: 16px;" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/koh-samet-bar.png" alt="Naga Bar" width="655" height="471"></h3>
<figure id="attachment_1153" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1153" style="width: 664px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/koh-samet-bar2.png" alt="Naga Bar Koh Samet" width="664" height="475"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1153" class="wp-caption-text">Naga Bar offers chilled atmosphere during the day and great party vibes at night</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Ao Prao beach</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Simply</strong>&nbsp;<strong>paradise</strong>. Surrounded by resorts, but don&#8217;t let this put you off. The water is a stunning shade of blue and crystal clear, and the sand couldn&#8217;t be any whiter. We&#8217;ve visited quite a few beaches, and this is one of our favorites. Plus, we got to witness one of the most beautiful sunsets we&#8217;ve ever seen. Pictures simply don&#8217;t do it justice—you&#8217;ll have to go and see it for yourself!</p>
<figure id="attachment_84" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-84" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet2-1024x683.jpg" alt="Koh Samet is worth a visit" width="690" height="460"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-84" class="wp-caption-text">This sunset alone shows Koh Samet is worth a visit</figcaption></figure>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/koh-samet-beach-day.jpg" alt="koh samet beach" width="4799" height="2887"></p>
<h3>Wat Koh Samet</h3>
<p>Buddism is an important part of the local culture, so if you want to experience that, the temple complex in the middle of the village called Wat Koh Samet is worth a visit. <strong>After climbing a few stars, you will find the famous big Buddha statue there.&nbsp;</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_93" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-93" style="width: 449px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet61-e1570995284982.jpg" alt="Koh Samet Wat" width="449" height="589"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-93" class="wp-caption-text">Make sure to stop on your way to visit the Big Buddha in Koh Samet Wat</figcaption></figure>
<p>If you are a morning person <strong>you may be lucky to see monks walking down the streets and receiving alms</strong>, as the practice of offering food is called. Mothers have been cooking food for monks and giving alms since the dawn of Buddhism over 2,500 years ago!</p>
<figure id="attachment_92" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-92" style="width: 3114px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180318_112606.jpg" alt="Monks in the morning" width="3114" height="2715"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-92" class="wp-caption-text">Monks receiving alms in the morning</figcaption></figure>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet-2-e1570995952859.jpg" alt="Mrrrau" width="440" height="549"></p>
<h2><strong>Accommodation</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>Budget option: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/stay-samed">Stay Samet</a></strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: left;">Looking for a budget-friendly accommodation option while exploring Koh Samet? Consider Stay Samet. They offer both shared and private rooms that are clean and comfortable. The on-site restaurant serves a variety of healthy and delicious food. The reception staff is friendly and always ready to assist with anything. Plus, the location is excellent, with many shops and restaurants nearby.</p>
<h4><strong>Comfort option</strong>: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/samed-villa-resort">Samed Villa Resort</a></h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a more luxurious stay while exploring Koh Samet, consider Samed Villa Resort. This outstanding resort is located right in front of Ao Phai Beach, providing direct access to the beach. You can enjoy the best sunsets right from the resort! The rooms are stylish and clean, and don&#8217;t forget to indulge in their massage service!</p>
<h2>How to come back to Bangkok?</h2>
<p>All good comes to an end. Head to the pier and hop on the first departing boat to come back to the mainland<b>.</b> There are boats departing every hour. The slow one is 50 bahts and takes about an hour.</p>
<p><strong>There are buses heading to Bangkok </strong>at the bus station next to the pier<b>. </b>The price is 150 baths and the drop-off point is Ekkamai Bus Station.</p>
<p>To sum it up, exploring Koh Samet is an adventure worth undertaking, and we hope you enjoy it as much as we did</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/20180526_205828_0001.png" alt="Hidden gems of Thailand" width="560" height="315"></p>
<p><em>You may also find it interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/why-koh-chang-is-the-best-island-in-thailand/">Why Koh Chang is the best island in Thailand</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/">Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ha Long Bay or Sapa: Choose Your Adventure</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/ha-long-bay-or-sapa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 21:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ha long]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halong bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trekking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Updated April 2023: Uncover the charm of northern Vietnam! Dive into our comprehensive guide to help you decide: Ha Long Bay or Sapa? Explore breathtaking landscapes and authentic experiences. Are you planning a trip to the north of Vietnam and find yourself torn between visiting the enchanting Ha Long Bay or the captivating Sapa? You&#8217;re [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/ha-long-bay-or-sapa/">Ha Long Bay or Sapa: Choose Your Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="152" class="elementor elementor-152">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-6aa470c elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="6aa470c" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-2dc2014" data-id="2dc2014" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
								</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-2307a3b elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="2307a3b" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-bd41ec1" data-id="bd41ec1" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-34a395c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="34a395c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p><i>Updated April 2023: Uncover the charm of northern Vietnam! Dive into our comprehensive guide to help you decide: Ha Long Bay or Sapa? Explore breathtaking landscapes and authentic experiences.</i></p><p>Are you planning a trip to the north of Vietnam and find yourself torn between visiting the enchanting Ha Long Bay or the captivating Sapa? You&#8217;re not alone. This is a common dilemma faced by many travelers due to the unique attractions each destination offers. But worry not, we&#8217;ve got you covered. We&#8217;ve explored both places and are here to help you make an informed decision.</p><p><span style="color: inherit; font-family: 'Nothing You Could Do'; font-size: 40px; font-weight: 900;">Price Considerations</span></p><p>When deciding between Ha Long Bay or Sapa, it&#8217;s essential to consider your budget. Both destinations offer a variety of packages, but generally, Ha Long Bay tends to be a more expensive experience.</p><p>For Sapa, prices range from $40 to $75 for a 1-night and 2-day trek, including a homestay in a village. The group size usually ranges from 2 to 6 people. For the same price, you can only manage day-trips to Ha Long Bay. A 1-night and 2-day experience in Ha Long Bay will cost around $80 to $250, depending on the cruise you choose.</p><p><strong>What we picked:</strong> For Sapa, we chose <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/vn/sapa-o-39-chau-sapa.html?aid=1535401&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Sapa O’Chau</a> </strong>and loved it. They promote  sustainable employment among the locals which is a plus for us. We chose the tour called “Off the beaten track” as we don’t like touristic activities and we paid 60$ each.</p><p> </p><p>Ha Long Bay is one of the “you get what you pay for” places. If you get a cheap one, you may end up in an awful boat with awful food, wishing the cruise finishes as soon as possible. Thus, we went <em>really </em>out of our budget and chose the package also called &#8216;Off the Beaten Track&#8217; offered by <a href="https://www.indochina-junk.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Indochina Junk</a> for 149$ per person. Important to note that most of the cruises sleep in Ha Long Bay, along with thousands of boats. Choosing that package we wanted to avoid the crowds- our cruise spent the night on Bai Tu Long Bay with only a few boats on the horizon. The boat was pretty good and included a very comfortable transportation from Hanoi. <span style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );"> </span></p><p></p><p><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/indochina-junk.png" alt="Ha Long Bay or Sapa?" width="859" height="552" /></p><h4 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Price: easy win for Sapa</strong><strong> </strong></h4><h2><strong>Experience</strong></h2><p>Your expectations and what you&#8217;re looking for in your travel experience are crucial factors when choosing between Ha Long Bay or Sapa.</p><p>Sapa was one of the highlights of our trips. Our guide and homestay were simply incredible. We learned so much about her village and tribe, the landscape was breathtaking, and the food was authentic. Most importantly, we didn’t see a single tourist for 2 days. When we left Sapa, we felt like leaving our second home, but we were full of joy thanks to Xuan, our guide. The connection you create with the place and people during these 2 days of trekking is amazing.Apri</p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-a896d44 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="a896d44" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-33 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-92faeba" data-id="92faeba" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-91ea9c8 elementor-button-info elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="91ea9c8" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a class="elementor-button elementor-button-link elementor-size-sm" href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">If you want to know more about our experience in Sapa, check out this post</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-66 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-d432baa" data-id="d432baa" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9f3e991 elementor-view-default elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon" data-id="9f3e991" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-icon-wrapper">
			<div class="elementor-icon">
							<i class="fa fa-bookmark-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>
						</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-1b2a8bc9 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="1b2a8bc9" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-17a9e681" data-id="17a9e681" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-7c6973a9 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="7c6973a9" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h2><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08268.jpg" alt="Local in Sapa" width="2894" height="2303" /></h2><p><br />Ha Long Bay, on the other hand, is impressive, specially if you go for an expensive company. Our boat was beautiful. The food was AMAZING. The activities are alright, but not breathtaking. A couple of hours kayaking and visiting a fisherman village. They also let us swim for 30 minutes in open water, which was nice. We missed being able to swim at some beach but this is forbidden by the government. Obviously, you have no independence as everything is planned.<br /><span style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );"><br /></span></p><p><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08381.jpg" alt="The views were amazing" width="3600" height="2026" /></p><h4 style="text-align: center;"><b>Experience: Sapa wins by a little</b><b style="color: var( --e-global-color-text ); font-family: Montserrat; font-size: 14px;"> </b></h4><h2><strong>Comfort</strong></h2><p>If you&#8217;re going to Sapa, be prepared to trek mountains, sleep in a maybe not very comfortable homestay, get muddy if it rains, etc. For Ha Long Bay, you literally feel like Paris Hilton and you don’t need to move a finger. Just relax and enjoy the cruise!</p><p><img decoding="async" style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08358.jpg" alt="Rafa in the boat" width="3600" height="2026" /></p><h4 style="text-align: center;"><strong>Comfort: very easy win for Ha Long Bay</strong></h4><p style="text-align: center;"><strong> </strong></p><h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2><p>If you have the time and the budget, do BOTH. Especially because both experiences are unique and are so different from each other. However, If we had to choose only one, <strong>we would choose Sapa, </strong>just because we had a really authentic experience, one of those that makes travelling so rewarding.</p><p style="text-align: center;"><em>What would you choose? Have you already been to any of the two? We would love to hear about your experience!</em></p><p><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/sapa6.jpg" alt="Sapa mountains" width="4800" height="2606" /><img decoding="async" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08034-2.jpg" alt="Sapa in a sunny day is just too much" width="4800" height="2701" /></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-8f270d5 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="8f270d5" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-282a4f1" data-id="282a4f1" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6279e28 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="6279e28" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>If you enjoyed the post, share it!</strong></p><p style="box-sizing: inherit; color: #333333;"><em style="box-sizing: inherit;">You may also find it interesting…</em></p><ul><li style="color: #333333; box-sizing: inherit;"><em style="box-sizing: inherit;"><a style="box-sizing: inherit;" href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/why-koh-chang-is-the-best-island-in-thailand/">Why Koh Chang is the best island in Thailand</a></em></li><li style="color: #333333; box-sizing: inherit;"><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/travel-to-singapore-on-a-budget/">Travel to Singapore on a budget</a></li><li style="color: #333333; box-sizing: inherit;"><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/unforgettable-adventure-cycling-angkor-wat/">An Unforgettable Adventure: Cycling Angkor Wat</a></li></ul>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4790260 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4790260" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-cc4587f" data-id="cc4587f" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-a608324 elementor-widget elementor-widget-image" data-id="a608324" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="image.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-image">
												<img decoding="async" width="560" height="315" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/20180922_182024_0001.png" class="attachment-large size-large wp-image-863" alt="" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/20180922_182024_0001.png 560w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/20180922_182024_0001-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px" />														</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/ha-long-bay-or-sapa/">Ha Long Bay or Sapa: Choose Your Adventure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>30 bad things about long-term travelling that no one told you about</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/30-bad-things-about-long-term-travelling/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 08:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long-term travelling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>30 bad things about long-term travelling Travelling is amazing, it really is. But before you are ready to quit your job, grab your other half and hop onto a plane, these are our 30 bad things about long-term travelling that no one told you about 1. Although you may think you are better than that- you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/30-bad-things-about-long-term-travelling/">30 bad things about long-term travelling that no one told you about</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="600" class="elementor elementor-600 elementor-bc-flex-widget">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-3b51af45 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="3b51af45" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-3efe65e0" data-id="3efe65e0" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e844494 elementor-widget elementor-widget-counter" data-id="e844494" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="counter.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-counter">
			<div class="elementor-counter-number-wrapper">
				<span class="elementor-counter-number-prefix"></span>
				<span class="elementor-counter-number" data-duration="3000" data-to-value="30" data-from-value="30" data-delimiter=",">30</span>
				<span class="elementor-counter-number-suffix"></span>
			</div>
							<div class="elementor-counter-title">bad things about long-term travelling </div>
					</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3bd34de elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3bd34de" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 17.0pt; weight: 30.0pt; font-family: 'Nothing you could do','serif'; mso-fareast-font-family: 'Times New Roman'; color: windowtext; mso-fareast-language: EN-GB;">Travelling is amazing, it really is. But before you are ready to quit your job, grab your other half and hop onto a plane, these are our 30<b> </b>bad things about long-term travelling that no one told you about</span></h4>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-98c7276 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="98c7276" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-c35dbac" data-id="c35dbac" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-2e85592 elementor-align-left elementor-icon-list--layout-traditional elementor-list-item-link-full_width elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-list" data-id="2e85592" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-list.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<ul class="elementor-icon-list-items">
							<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-plane" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">1.	Although you may think you are better than that- you WILL miss a flight, it is just a matter of time.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-heartbeat" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">2. You will get sick and freak out it is malaria or dengue fever...but it is just a food poisoning. And probably with the meal that you expect the least (hamburger with chips, yep!).</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-map" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">3.	It's a full-time job and you will spend days organizing itineraries (AND YOUR GIRLFRIEND PROBABLY DOESN'T HELP YOU). You will even consider becoming a travel agen.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-book" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">4.	At some point you will have problems with visas, either entering or leaving a country. <i>We had to spend 24 hours in HK airport awaiting Iga's urgent visa to be issued. BTW, this is how we missed our first flight</i> </span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-suitcase" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">5. The transition from a 2 bedroom flat to one backpack is liberating but tricky. You will most surely pack way too much stuff and your backpack weights more than a baby elephant. One by one, you will throw away that "extra thing in case we need it" and regret taking it with you in the first place. </span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-home" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">6.	You will get homesick, everyone does. "I want to sleep in, wear pyjamas all day long watching Netflix on my sofa" type of thing</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-battery-quarter" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">7.	You will understand long-term travelling is exhausting. Really, it is.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-users" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">8.	You will miss your best friends as hell, and the time difference does not help.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-plug" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">9.	HOW MANY PLUG ADAPTERS EXIST?</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-codiepie" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">10.	There will be days when you'll miss your comfort food so much that you will end up paying double for the "Italian" pizza that tastes like a chewing gum (pizza in Asia sucks)</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-user-times" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">11.	Soon enough you will realize that most of your friends don't really care about your "one in a lifetime adventure". They are busy living their lives and will hate you for all the cool pics you post on IG. They will divide into "that is so amazing guys, I want to travel like you!" and those who jealously think that you have rich parents or secretly won a lottery. </span>
									</li>
						</ul>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-eab8c2b elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="eab8c2b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-6f49a31 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="6f49a31" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-33 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-b54c7b4" data-id="b54c7b4" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6b8105e elementor-button-info elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="6b8105e" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a class="elementor-button elementor-button-link elementor-size-sm" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/30/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">FYI: if you want to find out how we managed to visit SE Asia on a limited budget- check this post</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
				<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-66 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-0f5a29f" data-id="0f5a29f" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-28837af elementor-view-default elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon" data-id="28837af" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-icon-wrapper">
			<div class="elementor-icon">
							<i class="fa fa-star" aria-hidden="true"></i>
						</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-f8da299 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="f8da299" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-aa8d7ad" data-id="aa8d7ad" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-615bdf5 elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="615bdf5" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-59f203b elementor-icon-list--layout-traditional elementor-list-item-link-full_width elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-list" data-id="59f203b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-list.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<ul class="elementor-icon-list-items">
							<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-question" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">12.	There will be days when you will join that second group in though self-criticism and will question your life choices. "It is time to grow up and get a 9-5 job" type of thing.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-dollar" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">13.	Borders are stressful, it doesn't matter how well prepared you are. Forget about the western standards, corruption does exist.</span>
									</li>
						</ul>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-dae99ec elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="dae99ec" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-f2b9df4 elementor-button-info elementor-align-center elementor-widget elementor-widget-button" data-id="f2b9df4" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="button.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-button-wrapper">
			<a class="elementor-button elementor-button-link elementor-size-sm" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/07/crossing-the-cambodian-border/" target="_blank">
						<span class="elementor-button-content-wrapper">
						<span class="elementor-button-text">Crossing the border in Cambodia was quite an experience... check our post to see if it is as bad as people say</span>
		</span>
					</a>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e7d22ed elementor-widget-divider--view-line elementor-widget elementor-widget-divider" data-id="e7d22ed" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="divider.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-divider">
			<span class="elementor-divider-separator">
						</span>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-e99909a elementor-icon-list--layout-traditional elementor-list-item-link-full_width elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-list" data-id="e99909a" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-list.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<ul class="elementor-icon-list-items">
							<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-venus-mars" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">14. If you are travelling with your couple, it is a matter of time you will want to kill each other a few times per day until you learn how to laugh about it.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-life-saver" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">15.	Travelling will verify, if it was your LIFE that really needed a change, or if it is YOU who was the problem. Get ready for some serious self-discovery moments and facing the real you.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-bus" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">16.	You will spend days stuck on never-ending bus rides or airports</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-taxi" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">17.	NO, NOT INTERESTED IN YOUR TUK-TUK OR TAXI, I had legs the last time I checked.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-credit-card-alt" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">18.	You will lose your wallet, credit card or phone. Or they will get stolen. Both equally bad.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-wifi" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">19. One of the bad things about long-term travelling is that you will become obsessed with having a decent internet connection.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Incognito-Natural-Mosquito-Insect-Repellent/dp/B001EJOHYG/ref=sr_1_10_a_it?ie=UTF8&#038;qid=1532490392&#038;sr=8-10&#038;keywords=anti+mosquitoes">

												<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-flash" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">20.	MOSQUITOES EVERYWHERE.</span>
											</a>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-paw" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">21.	The number of homeless dogs on the streets will break your heart (and your girlfriend will want to adopt them all)</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-meh-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">22.	People will only see the amazing bits about your travelling but no one realizes that you had to eat instant noodles for a week to recover your budget after losing a flight to Vietnam.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-money" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">23.	Locals see you like a dollar machine, trying to squeeze every penny out of you. Bargaining will become your second nature to the point that you will question pricetags in every supermarket.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-recycle" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">24.	You get tired of wearing the same clothes every day...</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-tint" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">25.	...and "how come we need a laundry again?"</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-camera-retro" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">26.	Your girlfriend takes WAY TOO MANY photos...</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-frown-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">27.	...and your boyfriend BARELY TRIES to pose for them.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-cloud-upload" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">28.	Then most surely you will lose half of them because your SD card will get damaged. Even if you are really tidy like us and save copies in the cloud, it will feel like a full-time job.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-heart-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">29.	You will get heartbroken at least a few times because of leaving amazing people and places behind.</span>
									</li>
								<li class="elementor-icon-list-item">
											<span class="elementor-icon-list-icon">
																<i class="fa fa-calendar-times-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>
													</span>
										<span class="elementor-icon-list-text">30.	Last but not least, on our top 30 bad things about long-term travelling for us is - <b>when you realise that it is coming to an end! </b>So don't take it for granted and remind yourself every day how lucky you are.</span>
									</li>
						</ul>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-8f433c1 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="8f433c1" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-27f3923" data-id="27f3923" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-53cdcf6 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="53cdcf6" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p style="line-height: normal; text-align: left;"><span style="color: #54595f; white-space: pre-wrap;">The silver lining is that long-term travelling is so worth it. It makes you a better person: more open-minded, inspired and willing to take risks. It is the best life lesson you will ever get. When you will be 80 years old, you will not remember the 6 months you spent in the office, but the awesome times you had while travelling in South East Asia, South America, Africa or Europe.</span></p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
				<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9ff23db elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="9ff23db" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"><span style="color: #54595f; white-space: pre-wrap;">Now that you know all the bad things about long-term travelling, if it didn&#8217;t kill your wanderlust- it means you are one of us!</span></p><p style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"><span style="color: #54595f; white-space: pre-wrap;">Set free and explore the world!</span></p><p style="line-height: normal; text-align: center;"> </p>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4ec1048 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4ec1048" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-744d5ce" data-id="744d5ce" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-9e02eb0 elementor-view-default elementor-mobile-position-top elementor-vertical-align-top elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-box" data-id="9e02eb0" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-box.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-icon-box-wrapper">
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-icon">
				<a class="elementor-icon elementor-animation-" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/30/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/">
				<i class="fa fa-heart-o" aria-hidden="true"></i>				</a>
			</div>
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-content">
				<h3 class="elementor-icon-box-title">
					<a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/30/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/" >
						Limited budget? 					</a>
				</h3>
									<p class="elementor-icon-box-description">
						Make sure you check our 3 rules to travel cheap for authentic experience seekers​					</p>
							</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/30-bad-things-about-long-term-travelling/">30 bad things about long-term travelling that no one told you about</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 06:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sapa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trekking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tribe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost///?p=392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As an ethnographer, I am always interested in reaching the people who still live by their traditions to understand their culture and the way they see the world. And meeting the Hill Tribes of Sapa was on my bucket list for Vietnam! Before going to Sapa, a town in the North of Vietnam, we were [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/">Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="392" class="elementor elementor-392 elementor-bc-flex-widget">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-2ac8c492 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="2ac8c492" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-723a9f6e" data-id="723a9f6e" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-73129fa2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="73129fa2" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p dir="ltr">As an ethnographer, I am always interested in reaching the people who still live by their traditions to understand their culture and the way they see the world. And meeting the Hill Tribes of Sapa was on my bucket list for Vietnam!</p><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Before going to Sapa, a town in the North of Vietnam, we were warned that it is packed with tourists and locals doing everything to sell you &#8220;handmade&#8221; souvenirs. Which, by the way, proved true. <strong>But if you only dare to go off the beaten track like we did, you will be able to discover the <em>real</em> hill tribes.</strong></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">Kids walking their buffalo at the dusk, men working in the rice fields. Mothers with their babies waving to you from their homes. Idyllic. All of them wearing traditional clothes &#8211; not for tourists, but because this is how things were since they came to Vietnam from China ages ago.</div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><div dir="auto">Get lost and discover the authentic life of Hill Tribes of Sapa, this world will mesmerise you.</div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto"><p>The price you will pay is sweat, sweat and sweat. Hills are difficult to climb in a summer heat, but that only makes you appreciate the breathtaking views of the rice fields mountains even more.</p><p> </p><p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-874 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7.jpg" alt="Sapa rice fields" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7.jpg 640w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p></div><div dir="auto"><h1>We met the authentic Hill Tribes of Sapa thanks to Xuan, our guide from the Red Dao tribe</h1><p>Like most girls in the village, she got married when she was very young. In many villages there is a place called &#8220;love market&#8221;, where teenagers are allowed to meet and get to know each other with the permission of their parents. If they fell in love and feel like it is a good match, the boy asks parents to marry their daughter. And her parents accepted.</p><p>In a patriarchal society, the bride always moves in with the groom&#8217;s parents. Imagine you are preparing a lunch for the whole family, and you don&#8217;t know how to pack rice in the banana leaves. I asked: &#8220;why didn&#8217;t you ask your mother how to do that?&#8221;. &#8220;There was no phone in the village, and I had moved far away from my family, so I had to learn by myself&#8221;, she said. And this is pretty much the definition of Xuan &#8211; all she achieved is thanks to herself!</p></div><h1 dir="auto">Every tribe has its own traditional textiles and clothing</h1><div dir="auto">Parents rarely refuse the marriage, if so, it is probably because the boy is from another village or tribe. You would say, &#8220;why does it matter if they live next to each other anyway?&#8221;</div><strong><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-361 alignleft" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-731x1024.jpg" alt="" width="166" height="233" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-731x1024.jpg 731w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-214x300.jpg 214w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-768x1075.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 166px) 100vw, 166px" /></strong><div dir="auto"><strong>In the Dao culture where worshipping your ancestors is the main religion (shamanism), providing the continuity of tradition is almost an obligation. </strong>On a very rare occasion, the young wife coming from a different tribe will learn it the hard way. Among many things, wife&#8217;s responsibility is to make traditional handmade clothes for the family, and as they vary a lot between tribes, she would be in a pickle.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">Honestly, the level of detail and embroidery is outstanding. <strong>Look at that dress Xuan made herself for her little daughter. It took her over 3 months!</strong></div><div dir="auto"><strong> </strong></div><h1 dir="auto">Shamanism in practice</h1><div dir="auto">For all Hill Tribes of Sapa ancestors blessing is important, it can provide you with a happy life. You have to watch out not to mistreat them (I am talking about <em>ghosts</em>, yes). <b>For example, after finishing your meal in the fields you should never leave banana leaves (with rests from the meal) in a place where buffalo can eat them.</b> You are not wrong, buffalo&#8217;s stomach can take some banana leaves with rice pretty well, however it would mean that ancestors will get full and won&#8217;t &#8220;send&#8221; any food for their family.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">As we passed by a dead snake on our hike, I asked Xuan if there is any animal that they consider particularly important. She said &#8220;buffalo&#8221;. The surprising connection between buffalo getting his stomach full and ancestors not being hungry anymore would most surely confirm that!</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-378 aligncenter" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08160.jpg" alt="DSC08160" width="593" height="396" /></div><div dir="auto"><p>We were able to ask her all sorts of things, as her English is amazingly good,  especially for someone who went only to a primary school because parents could not afford her further education. She is the only person in the whole village that speaks English and she learned it herself by memorizing a new word every day (no Internet in the village FYI!).</p></div><h1 dir="auto">Discovering feminism in Hill Tribes of Sapa</h1></div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto"><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Until now, no one in the village (apart from her husband) comprehends completely what she is doing. Trekking all day in the burning sun with &#8220;Europeans&#8221;? Why would they pay you for that? Some ask her husband: aren&#8217;t you worried that she is out there? She just laughs at that. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">A tender, loving mother and an amazing wife. She believes men and women are equal and she puts it into practice. With everything she does, she trusts herself: &#8220;listen to what people say like it&#8217;s the wind- goes in one ear, goes out another&#8221;.</span></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Xuan fascinated me as a woman. She managed to respect the tradition and yet, live her own way.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><strong>As I listened to her one night, I realised that it is what the <em>feminism</em> is all about, ladies. It is easy to refuse everything that culture enforces on you as a woman like we can afford to do nowadays in a western world. Be as independent, manly, strong as we want. What is hard though, is to be the first one that dares to be different in a small, traditional community.</strong></div></div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-380 aligncenter" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08213.jpg" alt="DSC08213" width="497" height="751" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Cheerful, hard-working, grateful, and yet fearless. This is Xuan, a woman that leads the past gently into the future&#8230; wearing sneakers and embroidered Dao trousers.</div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><h1 dir="auto"><strong>How to enjoy Sapa with Xuan</strong></h1><div dir="auto">Xuan May is one of the guides of <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/vn/sapa-o-39-chau-sapa.html?aid=1535401&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Sapa O&#8217;Chau</a>. </strong>She does the trekking called &#8220;Off the beaten track&#8221;, so when booking just you make sure you ask for that trekking with her. To get there, you can do it by <a href="https://12go.asia/en/train/hanoi/sapa/?z=1511837&amp;sub_id=sapatrain"><strong>train</strong></a> or <strong><a href="https://12go.asia/en/bus/hanoi/sapa/?z=1511837&amp;sub_id=sapabus">bus.</a> </strong>We got a sleeper bus for a night ride and it was very comfortable (only 10$ per person).</div><div dir="auto"> </div><h1 dir="auto">Day 1 (17km)</h1><div><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-873 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa6.jpg" alt="Sapa" width="640" height="347" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">You will be picked up in Sapa town around 8 am and taken a little bit up the hills in a van. The trekking starts in a small village and you will be the only tourist there (it is truly off the beaten track). There are 17 km of hiking ahead of you, but the views will make it worth! The journey will take you thorough mountains, valleys, forests and terraced rice fields.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><b>TIP:</b></div><div dir="auto">Because the trekking will last the whole day, wear comfortable clothes and shoes and don&#8217;t take a massive backpack. You won&#8217;t need much anyway- clothes for the next day, basic toiletry and a camera to capture these amazing views! Don&#8217;t forget the sunscreen.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">You will have lunch in an amazing setting &#8211; up the  hills with a panoramic view of Ban Khoang valley.</div><div dir="auto">After arriving to Xuan&#8217;s village and getting some rest you will have dinner with her family- the food was amazing!</div><div dir="auto"> </div><h1 dir="auto">Day 2 (12km)</h1><div dir="auto">Rise and shine! Time to go down and appreciate the views of rice fields in the mountains. We haven&#8217;t seen a single tourist during these 2 days, but plenty of locals from various tribes that greet you with a smile.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">The trek ends around 3 pm in Sapa town. Just on time to have a quick shower and catch a bus back to Hanoi.</div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-814 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa3-1024x615.jpg" alt="Sapa" width="640" height="384" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-815 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa2-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="427" /></div>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-f4ddd8b elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="f4ddd8b" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6b81a11" data-id="6b81a11" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6877183 elementor-view-default elementor-mobile-position-top elementor-vertical-align-top elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-box" data-id="6877183" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-box.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-icon-box-wrapper">
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-icon">
				<span class="elementor-icon elementor-animation-" >
				<i class="fa fa-star" aria-hidden="true"></i>				</span>
			</div>
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-content">
				<h3 class="elementor-icon-box-title">
					<span  >
						Hope you enjoyed our post					</span>
				</h3>
									<p class="elementor-icon-box-description">
						If you decided to meet Xuan in Sapa, let us know and leave a comment!					</p>
							</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/">Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Following the crowd at Shibuya crossing in Tokyo</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/shibuya-crossing-in-tokyo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 15:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibuya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shibuya crossing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokyo]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you heard of the famous Shibuya crossing in Tokyo? The Shibuya crossing in Tokyo is rumoured to be the busiest intersection in the world. With more than 3000 people crossing it at peak times and coming from all directions at once, this place is any photographer&#8217;s dream. This is why it has become one [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/shibuya-crossing-in-tokyo/">Following the crowd at Shibuya crossing in Tokyo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Have you heard of the famous Shibuya crossing in Tokyo?</h3>
<p>The Shibuya crossing in Tokyo is rumoured to be the busiest intersection in the world. With more than 3000 people crossing it at peak times and coming from all directions at once, this place is any photographer&#8217;s dream. This is why it has become one of the most popular sightseeing attractions in Tokyo, especially at night, when the flashing lights make it simply special.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Shibuya crossing in Tokyo has appeared in many movies, such as Lost in Translation, The Fast and the Furious or Resident Evil.</p></blockquote>
<p>A Japanese friend told me once that if you go to Tokyo and don&#8217;t cross it at least a few times you can&#8217;t really say you&#8217;ve been to Tokyo. I have to admit it looks hectic from outside, but from inside it feels really natural. It&#8217;s just one of many examples of how polite and organised is the Japanese culture and its people.</p>
<p><iframe title="Getting lost in Shibuya crossing crowd" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3EfIAL_O4EI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Everyone, including you, is waiting patiently for the green light. Once you step your foot down the zebra and follow the immense crowd, you realise that you participate in a live metaphor of the city- bursting with life and so crowded yet full of harmony and politeness. Thousands of people crossing in all directions within a few minutes and yet no one will bump into each other! Simply Zen.</p>
<p>We were a bit unlucky and spent a few very rainy days in Tokyo. With not much to do, we decided to come back to enjoy the rainy view from a Starbucks coffee on the second floor of a surrounding building. The sea of yellow umbrellas was just so cool.</p>
<p><iframe title="Umbrellas on Shibuya crossing" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iXFYIb1g2Mw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-238 size-full aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc07078.jpg" alt="Parorama photo of Shibuya crossing in Tokyo " width="4800" height="2701" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc07078.jpg 4800w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc07078-300x169.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc07078-768x432.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc07078-1024x576.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4800px) 100vw, 4800px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>What about you? Have you been at the Shibuya crossing in Tokyo? We would love to know your thoughts!</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/shibuya-crossing-in-tokyo/">Following the crowd at Shibuya crossing in Tokyo</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our 3 rules to travel CHEAP for experience seekers</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/</link>
					<comments>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 07:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couchsurfing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homestay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hostalworld]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travelhacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trustedhousesitters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uber]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There is this false belief, that you must be rich in order to travel. When explaining to some acquaintances how long we were gonna travel for, some of them would react like &#8220;Wow, you guys are loaded!&#8220;. We are far from being loaded! The funny thing is, those who say that probably go on holidays [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/">Our 3 rules to travel CHEAP for experience seekers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is this false belief, that you must be rich in order to travel. When explaining to some acquaintances how long we were gonna travel for, some of them would react like &#8220;<em>Wow, you guys are loaded!</em>&#8220;. We are far from being loaded! The funny thing is, those who say that probably go on holidays for 2 weeks, spending the same money than us in 2 months! That&#8217;s why we want to share our 3 rules to travel cheap!</p>
<p><strong>We&#8217;ve discovered that spending more money usually doesn&#8217;t make your trip any better, in fact, if anything, it makes it less authentic.</strong></p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;I only have 2 weeks of holidays per year. I an definitively staying in that 5 stars hotel, look at that bath tube!&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<h2><strong>1. Choose your destination wisely</strong></h2>
<p>Let&#8217;s be honest, your holidays are going to depend a lot on the country you are at. It&#8217;s not the same to visit Myanmar than visiting Switzerland. Whenever you go somewhere expensive, be aware that there is a tradeoff&#8230;</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">Moving by taxi if you feel tired vs public transport, meaning you end up exhausted every day</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Eating wherever you feel into vs. eating in McDonald&#8217;s because you can&#8217;t afford anything else (e.g. Hong Kong is famous for its super cheap Michelin Star restaurants!)</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Boat to that magic cave + kayaking + cooking lesson + motorbike tour vs free walking tour around the city</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">You get the idea&#8230;</li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_122" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-122" style="width: 278px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-122" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20180421_094233.jpg" alt="Rules to travel cheap: Don't do Japanese trains" width="278" height="370" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_094233.jpg 3000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_094233-225x300.jpg 225w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_094233-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 278px) 100vw, 278px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-122" class="wp-caption-text">Two-week railway pass in Japan can ruin anyone&#8217;s budget&#8230; BTW, bullet trains are amazing <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">Thus, one of the most important rules to travel cheap is to <strong>choose countries that are considered cheap for your budget</strong>. This does not mean you can&#8217;t go to, let&#8217;s say Japan, for 3 weeks and still make it affordable like we did.&nbsp; However, for the same money, you could spend 6 weeks in Thailand without counting every penny!</p>
<h2><strong>2. Accommodation</strong></h2>
<p>The next of our rules to travel cheap is to&nbsp;<strong>stay away from hotels</strong>. Hotels are usually expensive and they are not worth the money. Plus, who wants to stay in a room where you can&#8217;t really tell which country you are at? We like to have a local experience, which hotels don&#8217;t really give you. Our favourites alternatives:</p>
<h3><strong>Airbnb</strong></h3>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-121 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_181959812_hdr-1024x576.jpg" alt="Rules to travel cheap: AirBnb" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_181959812_hdr-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_181959812_hdr-300x169.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_181959812_hdr-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<figure id="attachment_120" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-120" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-120 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_182206681-1024x576.jpg" alt="Our beautiful flat in Porto" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_182206681-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_182206681-300x169.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20170414_182206681-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-120" class="wp-caption-text">Our beautiful flat in Porto</figcaption></figure>
<p>We find Airbnb great, as you get to stay in truly&nbsp;local places and, in seconds, you feel like you belong there. Say hi to new neighbours, get a morning coffee in the local shop, warm baguettes from the bakery around the corner, and fresh fruits from the food market nearby. We love to cook from time to time, it is a DIY way to experiment with the local cuisine and try out some new recipes.</p>
<p>Hosts usually try to help you as much as possible to get a positive review, so it&#8217;s a win-win. Fair to be said, Airbnb is not super cheap and the hassle of checking in/out it&#8217;s usually not worth it for short stays (1-2 nights). We go for Airbnb when we want to stay for the medium-long term (4-5 days at least).</p>
<figure id="attachment_127" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-127" style="width: 6000px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-127 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07028.jpg" alt="Rules to travel cheap: Our flat in Japan" width="6000" height="4000" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07028.jpg 6000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07028-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07028-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07028-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 6000px) 100vw, 6000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-127" class="wp-caption-text">Whenever we stay in Airbnb I can&#8217;t wait to get back to my morning routine (oh yes, routine sounds good when you travel non stop for a few months&#8230;)</figcaption></figure>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: left;"><strong>TIP</strong>: Many hosts offer you discounts for staying a week or a month. If you are thinking about staying 5-6 days, check how much would it be 7 days, as it may even be cheaper! Same thing with monthly stays.</p>
<h3><strong><a href="https://www.booking.com/index.html?aid=1530604">Booking.com</a></strong></h3>
<p>We use any of these services for short stays. If you are going 2 days-1 night somewhere, you aren&#8217;t going to spend much time in your room. Thus, just get something cheap, well-located, clean and move on. You really don&#8217;t need that Smart TV, you have it at home!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>TIP:</strong> Also, if possible, <strong>book&nbsp;your accommodation only a few days before arriving at your destination.</strong> Why? Hosts lose money when they have their place empty so they will be happy offering discounts. You may get up to 30-40% discount on the price! This also applies to Airbnb.</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.couchsurfing.com/"><strong>CouchSurfing</strong></a></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">At the beginning of our trip, we were a bit worried about staying for free in someone&#8217;s home, but we have to admit we were wrong. If you find the right host, it&#8217;s an unbelieve experience. Keep in mind these people invite strangers to their home for free, so they do it because they enjoy it!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-223" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20180421_170542new.jpg?w=1000" alt="Rules to travel cheap: COACHSURFING!" width="387" height="255" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_170542new.jpg 2592w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_170542new-300x198.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_170542new-768x506.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180421_170542new-1024x675.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 387px) 100vw, 387px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>TIP:</strong> Offer something in exchange to truly enjoy your stay &#8211; you can cook some local cuisine from your country or speak some English to their kids, it will make the best travel story.</p>
<blockquote><p>We couchsurfed in a Japanese house in Hiroshima&#8217;s countryside with a local family and ended up singing Karaoke while drinking Sake. What hotel is going to give you that? And FOR FREE!</p></blockquote>
<h3><a href="https://www.trustedhousesitters.com/su/UkcrbMQh"><strong>TrustedHouseSitter</strong></a></h3>
<h3><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-124" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/dsc03631.jpg?w=1366" alt="Our flat in Bangkok" width="602" height="903" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc03631.jpg 4000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc03631-200x300.jpg 200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc03631-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc03631-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></h3>
<p>Probably our favourite.</p>
<p><strong>With this platform, you go to someone&#8217;s home to take care of their pets while they are away &#8211; for free.</strong> You live in their home, meaning they are fully equipped and ready to have a very comfortable stay. Sometimes the houses are dream houses, you would not believe it.</p>
<p>Of course, you have to love animals, otherwise, this is not for you. <strong>You&#8217;ll be taking care of cats, dogs or pretty much anything they have at home.</strong> For us, this is far from being a problem, as we love animals and taking care of those 2 lovely brothers cats it&#8217;s the perfect excuse to travel to that paradise island.</p>
<figure id="attachment_125" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-125" style="width: 6000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-125 size-full" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/dsc03553.jpg" alt="Rules to travel cheap: pet sitting!" width="6000" height="4000"><figcaption id="caption-attachment-125" class="wp-caption-text">Be ready, these cuties will follow you everywhere</figcaption></figure>
<blockquote><p>Staying FOR FREE in Koh Samui (Thailand), chilling by the pool and playing with 2 lovely cats? Yeah, I&#8217;m in</p></blockquote>
<p>Keep in mind you&#8217;re not on holidays, meaning you should spend quality time with the animals and make sure they don&#8217;t miss their owners too much.</p>
<h2>3. Transport</h2>
<p>The last of our rules to travel cheap is, of course, related to transport. Some tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Don&#8217;t buy <strong>flights</strong> that are out of your budget. If possible, change your itinerary so you can fly cheaper. Never buy a flight without tracking for a few days how the price oscillates. Setting a <a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10641620"><strong>Skyscanner</strong></a> alarm for a flight or Kayak &#8220;buy&#8221; advice are usually very useful.</li>
<li>Whenever possible, take <strong>buses</strong> as they are way cheaper than planes.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Using a regular <strong>taxi</strong> in, let&#8217;s say Bangkok, it&#8217;s pretty challenging, and you&#8217;re very likely to get ripped off. Use <strong><a href="https://www.uber.com/invite/wted3">Uber</a></strong> or <strong><a href="https://r.grab.com/grabrafapiki">Grab</a></strong>. These apps make it really easy and they remove the language barrier. Happy times.</li>
</ul>
<p>To travel around Asia, services like <strong><a href="https://12go.asia/?z=1511837">12go</a></strong> are pure gold, as sometimes it can be challenging to buy tickets in a foreign country. Check it out!</p>
<p><strong>EXTRA TIP: Try to travel at night</strong>. We know sleeping on a bus or plane is not very comfortable, but you will save one night of accommodation. Plus, overnight trains are so romantic! If planning to visit Thailand, make sure to take a sleeper train on the classic route Bangkok &#8211; Chiang Mai. We loved it.</p>
<p><strong>Ok, these are our rules to travel cheap. However, we want to give you an extra piece of advice&#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong>4. Activities (for free)!</strong></p>
<p>Instead of splashing some cash on an expensive tour with a guide, do a quick search &#8211; chances are, there are some <strong>free city tours</strong> whenever you are!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-123" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/dsc07689-e1527181694820.jpg?w=892" alt="Rules to travel cheap: FREE activities with locals" width="554" height="360" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07689-e1527181694820.jpg 5207w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07689-e1527181694820-300x195.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07689-e1527181694820-768x498.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/dsc07689-e1527181694820-1024x665.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 554px) 100vw, 554px" /></p>
<p>One of the best experiences we have had so far in Vietnam was meeting Brian who showed us Hanoi on a free food tour (obviously the food was on us). He made us feel at home in a minute! By the way, that egg coffee was delicious!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">What are your tricks to travel good and cheap? Please share with us!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>If you liked it, please share it</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-420 aligncenter" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/horzons1.png" alt="" width="560" height="315"></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/">Our 3 rules to travel CHEAP for experience seekers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/3-rules-to-travel-cheap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 07:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angkor wat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[border]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh chang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poipet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siem reap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called Poipet, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called <strong>Poipet</strong>, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, but I&#8217;ll share our experience.</p>
<p><strong>Spoiler alert: It wasn&#8217;t as bad as they say it is!</strong></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Before crossing the Cambodian border</h2>
<p>We were in <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/26/koh-chang-a-hidden-paradise-of-thailand/"><strong>Koh Chang</strong></a>, an island on the Gulf of Thailand. We decided to travel to Cambodia, due to its proximity and to visit <strong>Angkor Wat</strong>, one of the most amazing monuments in the world.</p>
<p>While In Ko Chang, we stayed at <a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><strong>Little Eden Bungalows</strong></a>, a beautiful backpackers bungalow resort, where we were offered transportation to Siem Reap (the city where Angkor Wat is) through an external Thai company. The receptionist recommended not do the whole trip with them and get a taxi as soon as we reached Cambodia. This way we would avoid scams like: &#8220;Sorry the bus is broken, you all need to get these expensive taxis waiting conveniently for you in this corner&#8221;.</p>
<p>We had also read online to not even complete the whole trip in Thai side with them. They would do a stop before crossing the Cambodian border in a restaurant a few kilometres away, collecting everyone&#8217;s passports and forcing you to get the Cambodian visa through an unofficial office where you end up paying up to two times more!</p>
<p>The list of scams goes on and on, but we still decided to go for it. It was much cheaper and comfortable than coming all the way back to Bangkok and fly to Siem Reap.</p>
<p><strong>TIP: Don&#8217;t overread online about crossing the Cambodian border. </strong>YES, you need to do to make sure you read a bit to have everything under control. Once you&#8217;ve done that, stop reading. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll be like me; worried to death the night before and asking yourself why on earth you would do something like that. IT WILL BE OK <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The CROSSING day</h2>
<p>In the morning, a mini-van picked us up at 7 AM. The guy didn&#8217;t seem very friendly, but who cares, right? After picking up some tourists we made it to the pier, where we waited 30 minutes for the ferry. 45 minutes later we had made it to the mainland.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-191 size-full" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/koh-chang101.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: ready!" width="6000" height="4000" /></p>
<p>Back in the mini-van, we had a 3 hours drive ahead of us to <strong>Aranyaprathet</strong>, the Thai town where the border is. Turned up the stories were right and the guys took us to a restaurant where we &#8220;<em>would have lunch before going to the visa office</em>&#8220;. We said <em>&#8220;nope, thank you, we&#8217;ll walk&#8221;,</em> got our luggage and started walking. We had read they could get pushy when doing this but they were totally ok with it.</p>
<p>At this point, it was recommended to get a Tuk Tuk to the border, as the town is supposed to be dangerous. We didn&#8217;t see any (plus they would try to take us to the &#8220;unofficial office&#8221; to scam us), so we just walked. The town wasn&#8217;t <em>nice</em> but it didn&#8217;t feel dangerous either. Thai people taking care of their business and not a single person said anything to us. After 15 minutes we made it to the border. Happy times!</p>
<p>We were expecting long queues but it was clear we were way ahead than most of the tourists, which were probably stuck &#8220;having lunch&#8221;. In less than 10-15 minutes we had our leaving stamp in the passport and we were in Poipet, Cambodia.</p>
<p>Once there, some guys tried to help us out with our transport to Siem Reap as they &#8220;knew someone who could take us very cheap&#8221;. After ignoring them, we walked to the Visa Cambodian office where we would get our visa. Funny enough, we found again an empty office, full of Cambodian officers (around 10) and maybe 3-4 tourists. We filled up the requested documents, handed it to the officers along with a photo and&#8230;it was scam time again!</p>
<p><strong>The visa price is officially 30$</strong>, and even in the office, there is a big sign that says the same thing, 30$. We had read they would ask for more money and turned out to be right. The officer pointed to a very lame paper where we could read: <em>&#8220;30$ + 100 Baths&#8221;</em> (Bath is the Thai currency, 100 baths are about 3$). We said <em>&#8220;nope, it&#8217;s only 30$, is written there&#8221;</em>, but the guy didn&#8217;t even blink and repeated &#8220;<em>100 Baths</em>&#8220;. We tried to make him understand but he left us no choice, so we gave him the 100 baths.</p>
<blockquote><p>Trying to avoid the scam wasn&#8217;t really about the money but about playing by the book. Unfortunately, we didn&#8217;t have enough patience. If you hand out the 30$, sit and wait, after some time they will give you the visa. Who knows how long you will wait though.</p></blockquote>
<p>We walked a bit more and pass around a few casinos where Thai people gamble as it&#8217;s illegal in Thailand. Next step was to get the Cambodia entering stamp in our passport, which went quite smoothly. A random guy offered me a pen and of course, it turned out he knew a guy that would take us very cheap to Siem Reap. We got our stamps in our passports, walked out of the office and the &#8220;pen guy&#8221; was waiting for us. He offered a price of 45$ to <em>our hotel </em>(we were 3, as Nicky, an American friend we had met in Koh Chang, had joined us). After negotiating a bit, we agreed on 40$ (13$ each) and we were on our way to Siem Reap.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Crossing the Cambodian border: CHECKED!</h2>
<p>So far so good! But we knew it wasn&#8217;t over yet. Turns out you can&#8217;t really trust these guys at all. He didn&#8217;t take us to our hotels, but to a random place in the city where a guy in his Tuk Tuk came to pick us up. He would only take us for free if we hired him for the next day to visit Angkor Wat.</p>
<p>We said no and started to negotiate prices again. Our friend Nicky was staying in a different hostel, meaning the guy wasn&#8217;t happy about doing 2 stops. He wanted us to pay 5$ each to take us to the hostels (15$ in total), but we said we would take another Tuk Tuk and he finally settled in 10$. We would later find out that was still very pricey, but at that moment we didn&#8217;t care. 15 minutes later,<strong> we made it to our hostel safe and sound</strong>!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Summing up, if you&#8217;re thinking about crossing the Cambodian border by land, <strong>don&#8217;t stress and do it</strong>, it&#8217;s fine! We left Koh Chang at 7 AM and arrived at our hostel in Siem Reap at 5 PM<strong>. </strong>I can&#8217;t say it was a pleasant journey but it wasn&#8217;t that bad and<strong> it turned out to be a bit of fun.</strong> It&#8217;s sad neither the Thai nor Cambodian governments care about tourists being scammed as soon as they enter their countries. This shouldn&#8217;t stop you from enjoying what really is a beautiful country with beautiful people!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Accommodation</strong></h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for accommodation, we stayed at <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Velkommen Guesthouse</a>.</strong> It was cheap, nice (swimming pool!) and well located as it&#8217;s closer to Angkor Wat than most of the hostels. They provide free bikes so you can cycle to the city centre (10 minutes) or to Angkor Wat! 100% recommended it!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-215" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: safe and sound :)" width="467" height="831" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg 1166w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-169x300.jpg 169w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-576x1024.jpg 576w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 03:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[12goasia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh samui]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 options:</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348"><strong>Flight to Bangkok from Koh Samui</strong></a></h2>
<p>The most comfortable way but only for those travelling on a deep budget. Bangkok Airways runs this route many times during the day at around 130$ one way. The flight is 1hour 15 minutes and Bangkok Airways is spot on, including their tasty snack. Book here in <a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348">SkyScanner</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Bus</strong></a></h2>
<p>This option will take you to Bangkok in 12-13 hours depending on the starting port and the company. We have NOT done it but we&#8217;ve heard some opinions. It&#8217;s not <em>too</em> bad but keeps in mind you will be on a boat for a long time and then a long run in a bus will be waiting for you. Not much fun, especially on choppy days.</p>
<p>The price is around 1200฿-1400฿ (38-44$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Train</strong></a></h2>
<p>A bit more comfortable but very long, around 18 hours. A ferry will take you to the mainland and then by van, you will get to Suratthani train station. Then you need to take a train to Bangkok. The train goes from 18:37 to 06:30 so you can get some good sleep in the night.</p>
<p>The price goes from 2289฿ for a train first class ticket (72$) or 1758฿ for a second class ticket (55$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Flight</strong></a></h3>
<p>Our favourite, since it is good value on money, comfort and time. You could do the whole trip in around 6 hours depending on how long you need to wait for your flight. You&#8217;ll be taken from <strong>Na Thon </strong>port to mainland in a ferry run by <em>Seatran Ferry</em>. The ride is actually nice, safe boat and it has a bar where you can get some instant soups at a good price. After an hour and a half, you get to the mainland, where a van is waiting for you to take you to the airport. Once there you just need to take a flight to Bangkok.</p>
<p>There are very economics flights provided by Thai Smile (great) or Thai Lion (just ok). The price for the boat+van goes from 230฿ for the very early boats to 400฿, plus 30-40$ for the flight. In total, you will get spend around 40-50$, almost as cheap as the Ferry + Bus option but way more comfortable and fast. <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The last tip</strong>: make sure you find a proper way to get to the port. We used an app called NavigoApp (Uber/Grab style) because we were told it was way cheaper than normal taxis in Koh Samui. We paid 550฿ from Lamai Beach to Na Thon. However, some fellow travellers did the same trip using a regular taxi for 350฿. I think they just got lucky with the taxi driver, but overall our experience with NavigoApp was awful as the app barely work.</p>
<p>Happy travelling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-07-12 15:28:44 by W3 Total Cache
-->