<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iga, Author at It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/author/iga/feed/?simply_static_page=99223" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/author/iga/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:42:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>iga, Author at It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/author/iga/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[iga]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 06:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost///?p=392</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As an ethnographer, I am always interested in reaching the people who still live by their traditions to understand their culture and the way they see the world. And meeting the Hill Tribes of Sapa was on my bucket list for Vietnam! Before going to Sapa, a town in the North of Vietnam, we were [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/">Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="392" class="elementor elementor-392 elementor-bc-flex-widget">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
				<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-2ac8c492 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="2ac8c492" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-723a9f6e" data-id="723a9f6e" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-73129fa2 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="73129fa2" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
								<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix">
				<p dir="ltr">As an ethnographer, I am always interested in reaching the people who still live by their traditions to understand their culture and the way they see the world. And meeting the Hill Tribes of Sapa was on my bucket list for Vietnam!</p><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Before going to Sapa, a town in the North of Vietnam, we were warned that it is packed with tourists and locals doing everything to sell you &#8220;handmade&#8221; souvenirs. Which, by the way, proved true. <strong>But if you only dare to go off the beaten track like we did, you will be able to discover the <em>real</em> hill tribes.</strong></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">Kids walking their buffalo at the dusk, men working in the rice fields. Mothers with their babies waving to you from their homes. Idyllic. All of them wearing traditional clothes &#8211; not for tourists, but because this is how things were since they came to Vietnam from China ages ago.</div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><div dir="auto">Get lost and discover the authentic life of Hill Tribes of Sapa, this world will mesmerise you.</div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto"><p>The price you will pay is sweat, sweat and sweat. Hills are difficult to climb in a summer heat, but that only makes you appreciate the breathtaking views of the rice fields mountains even more.</p><p> </p><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-874 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7.jpg" alt="Sapa rice fields" width="640" height="360" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7.jpg 640w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa7-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p></div><div dir="auto"><h1>We met the authentic Hill Tribes of Sapa thanks to Xuan, our guide from the Red Dao tribe</h1><p>Like most girls in the village, she got married when she was very young. In many villages there is a place called &#8220;love market&#8221;, where teenagers are allowed to meet and get to know each other with the permission of their parents. If they fell in love and feel like it is a good match, the boy asks parents to marry their daughter. And her parents accepted.</p><p>In a patriarchal society, the bride always moves in with the groom&#8217;s parents. Imagine you are preparing a lunch for the whole family, and you don&#8217;t know how to pack rice in the banana leaves. I asked: &#8220;why didn&#8217;t you ask your mother how to do that?&#8221;. &#8220;There was no phone in the village, and I had moved far away from my family, so I had to learn by myself&#8221;, she said. And this is pretty much the definition of Xuan &#8211; all she achieved is thanks to herself!</p></div><h1 dir="auto">Every tribe has its own traditional textiles and clothing</h1><div dir="auto">Parents rarely refuse the marriage, if so, it is probably because the boy is from another village or tribe. You would say, &#8220;why does it matter if they live next to each other anyway?&#8221;</div><strong><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="wp-image-361 alignleft" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-731x1024.jpg" alt="" width="166" height="233" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-731x1024.jpg 731w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-214x300.jpg 214w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dsc08147-768x1075.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 166px) 100vw, 166px" /></strong><div dir="auto"><strong>In the Dao culture where worshipping your ancestors is the main religion (shamanism), providing the continuity of tradition is almost an obligation. </strong>On a very rare occasion, the young wife coming from a different tribe will learn it the hard way. Among many things, wife&#8217;s responsibility is to make traditional handmade clothes for the family, and as they vary a lot between tribes, she would be in a pickle.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">Honestly, the level of detail and embroidery is outstanding. <strong>Look at that dress Xuan made herself for her little daughter. It took her over 3 months!</strong></div><div dir="auto"><strong> </strong></div><h1 dir="auto">Shamanism in practice</h1><div dir="auto">For all Hill Tribes of Sapa ancestors blessing is important, it can provide you with a happy life. You have to watch out not to mistreat them (I am talking about <em>ghosts</em>, yes). <b>For example, after finishing your meal in the fields you should never leave banana leaves (with rests from the meal) in a place where buffalo can eat them.</b> You are not wrong, buffalo&#8217;s stomach can take some banana leaves with rice pretty well, however it would mean that ancestors will get full and won&#8217;t &#8220;send&#8221; any food for their family.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">As we passed by a dead snake on our hike, I asked Xuan if there is any animal that they consider particularly important. She said &#8220;buffalo&#8221;. The surprising connection between buffalo getting his stomach full and ancestors not being hungry anymore would most surely confirm that!</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-378 aligncenter" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08160.jpg" alt="DSC08160" width="593" height="396" /></div><div dir="auto"><p>We were able to ask her all sorts of things, as her English is amazingly good,  especially for someone who went only to a primary school because parents could not afford her further education. She is the only person in the whole village that speaks English and she learned it herself by memorizing a new word every day (no Internet in the village FYI!).</p></div><h1 dir="auto">Discovering feminism in Hill Tribes of Sapa</h1></div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto"><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">Until now, no one in the village (apart from her husband) comprehends completely what she is doing. Trekking all day in the burning sun with &#8220;Europeans&#8221;? Why would they pay you for that? Some ask her husband: aren&#8217;t you worried that she is out there? She just laughs at that. </span><span style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen-Sans, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif;">A tender, loving mother and an amazing wife. She believes men and women are equal and she puts it into practice. With everything she does, she trusts herself: &#8220;listen to what people say like it&#8217;s the wind- goes in one ear, goes out another&#8221;.</span></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Xuan fascinated me as a woman. She managed to respect the tradition and yet, live her own way.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><strong>As I listened to her one night, I realised that it is what the <em>feminism</em> is all about, ladies. It is easy to refuse everything that culture enforces on you as a woman like we can afford to do nowadays in a western world. Be as independent, manly, strong as we want. What is hard though, is to be the first one that dares to be different in a small, traditional community.</strong></div></div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-380 aligncenter" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/06/dsc08213.jpg" alt="DSC08213" width="497" height="751" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><div dir="auto">Cheerful, hard-working, grateful, and yet fearless. This is Xuan, a woman that leads the past gently into the future&#8230; wearing sneakers and embroidered Dao trousers.</div><div dir="auto"> </div></div><h1 dir="auto"><strong>How to enjoy Sapa with Xuan</strong></h1><div dir="auto">Xuan May is one of the guides of <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/vn/sapa-o-39-chau-sapa.html?aid=1535401&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Sapa O&#8217;Chau</a>. </strong>She does the trekking called &#8220;Off the beaten track&#8221;, so when booking just you make sure you ask for that trekking with her. To get there, you can do it by <a href="https://12go.asia/en/train/hanoi/sapa/?z=1511837&amp;sub_id=sapatrain"><strong>train</strong></a> or <strong><a href="https://12go.asia/en/bus/hanoi/sapa/?z=1511837&amp;sub_id=sapabus">bus.</a> </strong>We got a sleeper bus for a night ride and it was very comfortable (only 10$ per person).</div><div dir="auto"> </div><h1 dir="auto">Day 1 (17km)</h1><div><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-873 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa6.jpg" alt="Sapa" width="640" height="347" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">You will be picked up in Sapa town around 8 am and taken a little bit up the hills in a van. The trekking starts in a small village and you will be the only tourist there (it is truly off the beaten track). There are 17 km of hiking ahead of you, but the views will make it worth! The journey will take you thorough mountains, valleys, forests and terraced rice fields.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><b>TIP:</b></div><div dir="auto">Because the trekking will last the whole day, wear comfortable clothes and shoes and don&#8217;t take a massive backpack. You won&#8217;t need much anyway- clothes for the next day, basic toiletry and a camera to capture these amazing views! Don&#8217;t forget the sunscreen.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">You will have lunch in an amazing setting &#8211; up the  hills with a panoramic view of Ban Khoang valley.</div><div dir="auto">After arriving to Xuan&#8217;s village and getting some rest you will have dinner with her family- the food was amazing!</div><div dir="auto"> </div><h1 dir="auto">Day 2 (12km)</h1><div dir="auto">Rise and shine! Time to go down and appreciate the views of rice fields in the mountains. We haven&#8217;t seen a single tourist during these 2 days, but plenty of locals from various tribes that greet you with a smile.</div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto">The trek ends around 3 pm in Sapa town. Just on time to have a quick shower and catch a bus back to Hanoi.</div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-814 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa3-1024x615.jpg" alt="Sapa" width="640" height="384" /></div><div dir="auto"> </div><div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-815 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/sapa2-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="427" /></div>					</div>
						</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-f4ddd8b elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="f4ddd8b" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6b81a11" data-id="6b81a11" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-6877183 elementor-view-default elementor-mobile-position-top elementor-vertical-align-top elementor-widget elementor-widget-icon-box" data-id="6877183" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="icon-box.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-icon-box-wrapper">
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-icon">
				<span class="elementor-icon elementor-animation-" >
				<i class="fa fa-star" aria-hidden="true"></i>				</span>
			</div>
						<div class="elementor-icon-box-content">
				<h3 class="elementor-icon-box-title">
					<span  >
						Hope you enjoyed our post					</span>
				</h3>
									<p class="elementor-icon-box-description">
						If you decided to meet Xuan in Sapa, let us know and leave a comment!					</p>
							</div>
		</div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
									</div>
			</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/trekking-and-homestay-with-hill-tribes-of-sapa/">Trekking and homestay with Hill Tribes of Sapa</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-07-24 23:23:23 by W3 Total Cache
-->