<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cu chi tunnels Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi-tunnels/feed/?simply_static_page=72883" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi-tunnels/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 21:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Cu chi tunnels Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi-tunnels/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>One weekend couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/couchsurfing-in-ho-chi-minh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 06:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cu chi tunnels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ho chi minh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saigon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saigon english adventures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost///?p=399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Few days before our one month visa in Vietnam expired, we decided to finish our north-to-south trip doing something special: we wanted to spend our last days Couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh. This would give us the chance to spend some quality time with locals, something that we hadn&#8217;t managed so far for one reason or another. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/couchsurfing-in-ho-chi-minh/">One weekend couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Few days before our one month visa in Vietnam expired, we decided to finish our north-to-south trip doing something special: we wanted to spend our last days <strong>Couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh.</strong> This would give us the chance to spend some quality time with locals, something that we hadn&#8217;t managed so far for one reason or another.</p>
<p>This is how we found Thao, a girl who quitted her job to open <strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/SaigonEnglishAdventures/about/">Saigon English Adventures</a></strong>, an English school in Hoh Chi Minh, or better known as Saigon. She offers free accommodation at her place in exchange for volunteering in a few English classes with her students. We aren&#8217;t native speakers but we thought it should be good fun, so we applied. Thao promptly came back approving the stay. We were going to spend a few days interacting with Vietnamese people, exciting times!</p>
<p>She told us she would be away most of our stay as she was on holidays, so her roommate Jane would really be our host. We landed in Saigon from Da Nang at midnight, hopped into a Grab heading to the provided address. Jane picked us up with a huge smile and took us home. We would be sleeping in the living room, that turned out to be also the English school classroom!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Visiting Saigon</h2>
<p>Next day we woke up early and went out to do some sightseeing. We walked to the city center (also called District 1) to discover a bit of Saigon, a unique city. Crazy traffic with motorbikes everywhere, chickens in the street, motorbike taxi drivers taking naps on their bikes, etc. A huge pink Catholic church caught our attention, as we had never seen one like it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-569 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC09590-576x1024.jpg" alt="Pink church in Saigon" width="527" height="937" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC09590-576x1024.jpg 576w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC09590-169x300.jpg 169w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC09590-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC09590.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 527px) 100vw, 527px" /></p>
<p>After walking a while we got to the War Memorial Museum. There we had another lesson of how sad and unnecessary wars are. For lunch, we got some cheap Pho, you can&#8217;t beat the price! (30 Vietnamese dongs = 1.5$).</p>
<p>From lunch to evening we wandered around the city center, where we found the <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/24/the-strangest-protest-ever/">strangest protest we have ever witnessed</a>.</p>
<p>Next day we woke up early to visit the Cu Chi tunnels, one of the most popular attractions in Vietnam. If you want to read about this or you want to know how to visit the Cu Chi tunnels on our own, <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/15/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/">visit this post.</a> Once back from the tunnels, the most exciting part of the trip was about to start: English classes!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>English classes</h2>
<p>Jane told us the English teacher couldn&#8217;t make it to the class, meaning we had to drive the class with her help. Iga got a bit stressed about it but I was fine with it, I knew it was going to be so much fun!</p>
<p>One by one, the students started arriving. They were more or less on our age, a bit younger maybe. And you can&#8217;t imagine how cute they were! Their English was limited but they could communicate, especially because they were not shy at all, which makes everything much easier. The class ended up being 2 hours of &#8220;Ask me anything&#8221; and it was just so much fun. We also got to know a bit about each of them and we can tell they are beautiful people.</p>
<p>After the class, they invited us for dinner at a very Vietnamese restaurant. They ordered so much traditional food, which we obviously appreciated as sometimes can be daunting to try new food in exotic countries. We drank, laughed, ate, exchanged social media profiles, life experiences&#8230;and that was it! At the end of the night we were so happy with the experience, and also a bit sad because we could not stay any longer with them.</p>
<p>Next day we woke up and met Thao, the Couchsurfing host and the director of the school. We got to chat a bit with her, enough to be inspired by the happiness she emits. After having breakfast, we assisted her with a new English class. This group&#8217;s level was very basic, plus you could tell they weren&#8217;t very used to be with foreign people, so they were a bit shy. Still, it was also a lot of fun.</p>
<p>Spending the weekend Couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh was an amazing experience. It was exactly what we look for when traveling: visiting new places and meeting inspiring people, like Thao, Jane or their students. What about you? What do you look for when traveling?</p>
<p><iframe title="Dinner with: Saigon English Adventures" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HyFaMYQMASI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3 class="r"></h3>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/couchsurfing-in-ho-chi-minh/">One weekend couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 09:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cu chi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cu chi tunnels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ho chi minh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saigon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Going the Cu Chi tunnels on your own is something we recommend everyone to do when visiting Ho Chi Minh. The Cu Chi tunnels are an immense network of connecting underground tunnels that cover up to 250 km. Using these tunnels you could even get to Cambodia! They played a key role in the war to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/">How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going the <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%E1%BB%A7_Chi_tunnels">Cu Chi tunnels</a></strong> on your own is something we recommend everyone to do when <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/09/couch-surfing-in-ho-chi-minh/">visiting Ho Chi Minh</a>. The Cu Chi tunnels are an immense network of connecting underground tunnels that cover up to 250 km. Using these tunnels you could even get to Cambodia! They played a key role in the war to beat the Americans, who tried to destroy them many times but couldn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>To get there tourists usually hire a group tour but <strong>there is a way to get to the Cu Chi tunnels on your own.</strong> Most importantly, tours take tourists to a less authentic side of the tunnels, whereas going by yourself you get to the side where Vietnamese tourists go. Don&#8217;t worry, you will still get an English speaking guide. Ours was very funny!</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>How to get to the Cu Chi tunnels on your own</strong></h2>
<ol>
<li>Go to Pham Ngu Lao bus station.</li>
<li>Take bus number 13 that will take you to Ben Xe Cu Chi (last stop).</li>
<li>Get the bus 79 to Cu Chi tunnels.</li>
</ol>
<p>Bus tickets are <strong>7000 Vietnamese dongs</strong> each (0.3$), whereas tickets for the Cu Chi tunnels are <strong>90000 dongs</strong> (4$). English speaking guide included in the price.</p>
<p><strong>Funny fact</strong>: the buses don&#8217;t stop until the end of the journey, so it&#8217;s kind of a challenge to hop on/off the bus. I really felt bad for an old man trying to hop off, Vietnam is not a country for old men.</p>
<h2>The visit</h2>
<p>The visit shows how tough and driven the Vietnamese people were during the war. The tunnels are claustrophobic and crazy small. It&#8217;s incredible the Vietnamese managed to live for so long in a place like this. Everything was very well designed and thought of. They had hospitals, kitchens and leaders meeting rooms inside them. If one tunnel was bombed and compromised, the rest of the tunnels would be fine. And the list goes on and on.</p>
<p>Iga proved to be braver than me and entered in every single tunnel, while I only did it in a few. I&#8217;m going to make up an excuse and say I&#8217;m too tall (I&#8217;m not). There was one tunnel in which you could even hear a bat flying around haha. Nope, I&#8217;m not going in there sir!</p>
<p>At the end of the visit, you can shoot some guns if you&#8217;re into that (we aren&#8217;t). There is also a beautiful temple in honor of the war victims and Ho Chi Minh. We were lucky to see a school trip there, participating in a ceremony in Ho Chi Minh&#8217;s honor, singing and waving Vietnamese flag. Very patriotic, just like Vietnamese are!</p>
<p>If you liked it, share it!</p>
<p><iframe title="Cu Chi tunnels from inside" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TS7f0sO66iw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/11/03/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></h4>
</li>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/28/couchsurfing-in-ho-chi-minh/" rel="bookmark">One weekend couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh</a></h4>
</li>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/11/04/hanoi-worth-visiting/" rel="bookmark">Is Hanoi worth visiting? The ultimate 3 days guide</a></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/">How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-06-12 23:13:37 by W3 Total Cache
-->