<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cu chi Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi/feed/?simply_static_page=63519" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 21:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>cu chi Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/cu-chi/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rafag]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 09:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cu chi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cu chi tunnels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ho chi minh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saigon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Going the Cu Chi tunnels on your own is something we recommend everyone to do when visiting Ho Chi Minh. The Cu Chi tunnels are an immense network of connecting underground tunnels that cover up to 250 km. Using these tunnels you could even get to Cambodia! They played a key role in the war to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/">How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going the <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C%E1%BB%A7_Chi_tunnels">Cu Chi tunnels</a></strong> on your own is something we recommend everyone to do when <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/09/couch-surfing-in-ho-chi-minh/">visiting Ho Chi Minh</a>. The Cu Chi tunnels are an immense network of connecting underground tunnels that cover up to 250 km. Using these tunnels you could even get to Cambodia! They played a key role in the war to beat the Americans, who tried to destroy them many times but couldn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>To get there tourists usually hire a group tour but <strong>there is a way to get to the Cu Chi tunnels on your own.</strong> Most importantly, tours take tourists to a less authentic side of the tunnels, whereas going by yourself you get to the side where Vietnamese tourists go. Don&#8217;t worry, you will still get an English speaking guide. Ours was very funny!</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>How to get to the Cu Chi tunnels on your own</strong></h2>
<ol>
<li>Go to Pham Ngu Lao bus station.</li>
<li>Take bus number 13 that will take you to Ben Xe Cu Chi (last stop).</li>
<li>Get the bus 79 to Cu Chi tunnels.</li>
</ol>
<p>Bus tickets are <strong>7000 Vietnamese dongs</strong> each (0.3$), whereas tickets for the Cu Chi tunnels are <strong>90000 dongs</strong> (4$). English speaking guide included in the price.</p>
<p><strong>Funny fact</strong>: the buses don&#8217;t stop until the end of the journey, so it&#8217;s kind of a challenge to hop on/off the bus. I really felt bad for an old man trying to hop off, Vietnam is not a country for old men.</p>
<h2>The visit</h2>
<p>The visit shows how tough and driven the Vietnamese people were during the war. The tunnels are claustrophobic and crazy small. It&#8217;s incredible the Vietnamese managed to live for so long in a place like this. Everything was very well designed and thought of. They had hospitals, kitchens and leaders meeting rooms inside them. If one tunnel was bombed and compromised, the rest of the tunnels would be fine. And the list goes on and on.</p>
<p>Iga proved to be braver than me and entered in every single tunnel, while I only did it in a few. I&#8217;m going to make up an excuse and say I&#8217;m too tall (I&#8217;m not). There was one tunnel in which you could even hear a bat flying around haha. Nope, I&#8217;m not going in there sir!</p>
<p>At the end of the visit, you can shoot some guns if you&#8217;re into that (we aren&#8217;t). There is also a beautiful temple in honor of the war victims and Ho Chi Minh. We were lucky to see a school trip there, participating in a ceremony in Ho Chi Minh&#8217;s honor, singing and waving Vietnamese flag. Very patriotic, just like Vietnamese are!</p>
<p>If you liked it, share it!</p>
<p><iframe title="Cu Chi tunnels from inside" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TS7f0sO66iw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/11/03/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></h4>
</li>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/07/28/couchsurfing-in-ho-chi-minh/" rel="bookmark">One weekend couchsurfing in Ho Chi Minh</a></h4>
</li>
<li>
<h4 class="news-title"><a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/11/04/hanoi-worth-visiting/" rel="bookmark">Is Hanoi worth visiting? The ultimate 3 days guide</a></h4>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cu-chi-tunnels-on-your-own/">How to visit Cu Chi tunnels on your own</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-06-12 19:35:46 by W3 Total Cache
-->