<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>koh chang Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-chang/feed/?simply_static_page=72853" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-chang/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 22:46:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>koh chang Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-chang/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/</link>
					<comments>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bang Bao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klong Koi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh chang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koh Kut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Koh Mak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lonely Beach]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Note: This post was last updated on June 2023 to include the most current information and recommendations. If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note</strong>: This post was last updated on <strong>June 2023</strong> to include the most current information and recommendations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce competition, there are compelling reasons to believe that Koh Chang is one of the best islands in Thailand.</p>
<h2><strong>Getting to Koh Chang</strong></h2>
<p>Getting to Koh Chang might be a bit tricky as there&#8217;s no airport on the island. You can either fly to Trat&#8217;s airport from Bangkok and then take a taxi to Ao Thammachat&#8217;s port, where you can reach Koh Chang by sea in 30 minutes. Alternatively, you can take a bus from Ekkamai&#8217;s bus station in Bangkok, which takes around six hours (but is very comfortable!), and then catch a boat.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;re on the island, you can get around by taxi or by renting a motorbike. <strong>Exploring Koh Chang on a motorbike is one of our favorite memories from our trips around the world</strong>. It&#8217;s the best and cheapest option if you know how to drive.</p>
<p>Now, let&#8217;s dive into the best things to do in Koh Chang.</p>
<h2><strong>What to do</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>Klong Koi Beach</strong></h4>
<p>This beach is a paradise. The sand is amazing, and the water is surprisingly warm. On your way, visit Bang Bao Pier, where you can have a smoothie and do some shopping in the shops on the pier.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-184 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg" alt="koh chang " width="640" height="776" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg 845w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-248x300.jpg 248w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-768x931.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1267x1536.jpg 1267w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1690x2048.jpg 1690w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<h4><strong>Lonely Beach</strong></h4>
<p>While the beach in Lonely Beach is nothing special, the area is great for enjoying food or having some drinks. The atmosphere is very chilled during the day, although it can get a bit lively at night with some parties going on. Lonely Beach is also a great spot to enjoy sunrises. We enjoyed an awesome one at <a href="https://www.agoda.com/es-es/warapura-resort/hotel/koh-chang-th.html?finalPriceView=2&amp;isShowMobileAppPrice=false&amp;cid=1763310&amp;numberOfBedrooms=&amp;familyMode=false&amp;adults=2&amp;children=0&amp;rooms=1&amp;maxRooms=0&amp;checkIn=2023-06-12&amp;isCalendarCallout=false&amp;childAges=&amp;numberOfGuest=0&amp;missingChildAges=false&amp;travellerType=-1&amp;showReviewSubmissionEntry=false&amp;currencyCode=EUR&amp;isFreeOccSearch=false&amp;tag=3ca4e5ca-12bf-3f82-a5b3-51dd334b432a&amp;isCityHaveAsq=false&amp;los=1&amp;searchrequestid=d3196397-4a4e-4057-a418-7c2e442572b1">Warapura Resort</a>, which has happy hours in the early evening, making it the perfect spot to see the sunset.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-171 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-sunset-e1582292527691.jpg" alt="koh chang sunset" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<h4>Best Beaches in Koh Chang: White Sand, Khlong Prao, and Kai Bae</h4>
<p>These three beaches are some of the best places to visit in Koh Chang. White Sand Beach is the most popular and busiest beach on the island. It&#8217;s a great place to relax, swim, and enjoy the sun. There are plenty of restaurants and bars nearby, making it a lively place to spend the day.</p>
<p>Khlong Prao Beach is a bit quieter but equally beautiful. It&#8217;s a long, sandy beach that&#8217;s perfect for long walks and sunbathing. The beach is lined with coconut trees, adding to its tropical charm. There are also several resorts and restaurants nearby.</p>
<p>Kai Bae Beach is a hidden gem. It&#8217;s less crowded than the other two beaches, making it a great place to relax and enjoy the tranquility. The beach is surrounded by lush greenery, creating a serene and peaceful atmosphere.</p>
<h4>Exploring Khlong Phlu Waterfall: A Must-Do in Koh Chang</h4>
<p>If you get tired of beaches, you can go to Khlong Phlu, where you can have a nice short trek and enjoy sunbathing by a waterfall. You can dive in if you don&#8217;t mind the company of the small-medium fish!</p>
<p>Remember to wear sturdy shoes for the hike and bring some insect repellent to protect yourself from mosquitoes. There&#8217;s a small entrance fee to the national park, but it&#8217;s well worth it for the chance to see this beautiful waterfall.</p>
<h2>Accommodation</h2>
<h4><strong>Budget option: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.es.html">Little Eden Bungalows</a></strong></h4>
<p>For budget travelers, Little Eden Bungalows is a great option. Located in Lonely Beach, there are about 10 small bungalows. They also rent motorbikes for a good price (300 bahts).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-187 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg" alt="little eden" width="640" height="563" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg 1024w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-300x264.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-768x675.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1536x1349.jpg 1536w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-2048x1799.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>Comfort option</strong>: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.es.html">Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort</a></h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a bit more comfort, Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort is an excellent choice. With its excellent location, amazing pool, live music, delicious breakfast, and great sunsets, it&#8217;s an outstanding resort.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.en.html?aid=1593090&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=2"><img decoding="async" class="size-full aligncenter" src="https://q-cf.bstatic.com/images/hotel/max1280x900/162/162915342.jpg" width="1280" height="853" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>Embrace the Adventure</strong></h2>
<p>Remember, Koh Chang is one of those places where you don’t really need to worry about what to do. Just ride a motorbike and GET LOST. You can also visit Koh Mak and Koh Kut, the other islands in the archipelago. We&#8217;ve heard great things about them, but they are a bit far, so if you go, make sure you get some accommodation to spend the night and make the most of them.</p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">How to survive crossing Thai-Cambodian border</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/" rel="bookmark" data-wplink-url-error="true">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 07:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angkor wat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[border]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh chang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poipet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siem reap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called Poipet, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever heard about a town called <strong>Poipet</strong>, the chances are you didn&#8217;t hear anything good about it. There are horror stories online about crossing the Cambodian border from Thailand (and the other way around) by this town. I&#8217;m not going to list them as the Internet is flooded with posts about it, but I&#8217;ll share our experience.</p>
<p><strong>Spoiler alert: It wasn&#8217;t as bad as they say it is!</strong></p>
<h2></h2>
<h2>Before crossing the Cambodian border</h2>
<p>We were in <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/26/koh-chang-a-hidden-paradise-of-thailand/"><strong>Koh Chang</strong></a>, an island on the Gulf of Thailand. We decided to travel to Cambodia, due to its proximity and to visit <strong>Angkor Wat</strong>, one of the most amazing monuments in the world.</p>
<p>While In Ko Chang, we stayed at <a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><strong>Little Eden Bungalows</strong></a>, a beautiful backpackers bungalow resort, where we were offered transportation to Siem Reap (the city where Angkor Wat is) through an external Thai company. The receptionist recommended not do the whole trip with them and get a taxi as soon as we reached Cambodia. This way we would avoid scams like: &#8220;Sorry the bus is broken, you all need to get these expensive taxis waiting conveniently for you in this corner&#8221;.</p>
<p>We had also read online to not even complete the whole trip in Thai side with them. They would do a stop before crossing the Cambodian border in a restaurant a few kilometres away, collecting everyone&#8217;s passports and forcing you to get the Cambodian visa through an unofficial office where you end up paying up to two times more!</p>
<p>The list of scams goes on and on, but we still decided to go for it. It was much cheaper and comfortable than coming all the way back to Bangkok and fly to Siem Reap.</p>
<p><strong>TIP: Don&#8217;t overread online about crossing the Cambodian border. </strong>YES, you need to do to make sure you read a bit to have everything under control. Once you&#8217;ve done that, stop reading. Otherwise, you&#8217;ll be like me; worried to death the night before and asking yourself why on earth you would do something like that. IT WILL BE OK <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>The CROSSING day</h2>
<p>In the morning, a mini-van picked us up at 7 AM. The guy didn&#8217;t seem very friendly, but who cares, right? After picking up some tourists we made it to the pier, where we waited 30 minutes for the ferry. 45 minutes later we had made it to the mainland.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-191 size-full" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/koh-chang101.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: ready!" width="6000" height="4000" /></p>
<p>Back in the mini-van, we had a 3 hours drive ahead of us to <strong>Aranyaprathet</strong>, the Thai town where the border is. Turned up the stories were right and the guys took us to a restaurant where we &#8220;<em>would have lunch before going to the visa office</em>&#8220;. We said <em>&#8220;nope, thank you, we&#8217;ll walk&#8221;,</em> got our luggage and started walking. We had read they could get pushy when doing this but they were totally ok with it.</p>
<p>At this point, it was recommended to get a Tuk Tuk to the border, as the town is supposed to be dangerous. We didn&#8217;t see any (plus they would try to take us to the &#8220;unofficial office&#8221; to scam us), so we just walked. The town wasn&#8217;t <em>nice</em> but it didn&#8217;t feel dangerous either. Thai people taking care of their business and not a single person said anything to us. After 15 minutes we made it to the border. Happy times!</p>
<p>We were expecting long queues but it was clear we were way ahead than most of the tourists, which were probably stuck &#8220;having lunch&#8221;. In less than 10-15 minutes we had our leaving stamp in the passport and we were in Poipet, Cambodia.</p>
<p>Once there, some guys tried to help us out with our transport to Siem Reap as they &#8220;knew someone who could take us very cheap&#8221;. After ignoring them, we walked to the Visa Cambodian office where we would get our visa. Funny enough, we found again an empty office, full of Cambodian officers (around 10) and maybe 3-4 tourists. We filled up the requested documents, handed it to the officers along with a photo and&#8230;it was scam time again!</p>
<p><strong>The visa price is officially 30$</strong>, and even in the office, there is a big sign that says the same thing, 30$. We had read they would ask for more money and turned out to be right. The officer pointed to a very lame paper where we could read: <em>&#8220;30$ + 100 Baths&#8221;</em> (Bath is the Thai currency, 100 baths are about 3$). We said <em>&#8220;nope, it&#8217;s only 30$, is written there&#8221;</em>, but the guy didn&#8217;t even blink and repeated &#8220;<em>100 Baths</em>&#8220;. We tried to make him understand but he left us no choice, so we gave him the 100 baths.</p>
<blockquote><p>Trying to avoid the scam wasn&#8217;t really about the money but about playing by the book. Unfortunately, we didn&#8217;t have enough patience. If you hand out the 30$, sit and wait, after some time they will give you the visa. Who knows how long you will wait though.</p></blockquote>
<p>We walked a bit more and pass around a few casinos where Thai people gamble as it&#8217;s illegal in Thailand. Next step was to get the Cambodia entering stamp in our passport, which went quite smoothly. A random guy offered me a pen and of course, it turned out he knew a guy that would take us very cheap to Siem Reap. We got our stamps in our passports, walked out of the office and the &#8220;pen guy&#8221; was waiting for us. He offered a price of 45$ to <em>our hotel </em>(we were 3, as Nicky, an American friend we had met in Koh Chang, had joined us). After negotiating a bit, we agreed on 40$ (13$ each) and we were on our way to Siem Reap.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Crossing the Cambodian border: CHECKED!</h2>
<p>So far so good! But we knew it wasn&#8217;t over yet. Turns out you can&#8217;t really trust these guys at all. He didn&#8217;t take us to our hotels, but to a random place in the city where a guy in his Tuk Tuk came to pick us up. He would only take us for free if we hired him for the next day to visit Angkor Wat.</p>
<p>We said no and started to negotiate prices again. Our friend Nicky was staying in a different hostel, meaning the guy wasn&#8217;t happy about doing 2 stops. He wanted us to pay 5$ each to take us to the hostels (15$ in total), but we said we would take another Tuk Tuk and he finally settled in 10$. We would later find out that was still very pricey, but at that moment we didn&#8217;t care. 15 minutes later,<strong> we made it to our hostel safe and sound</strong>!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Summing up, if you&#8217;re thinking about crossing the Cambodian border by land, <strong>don&#8217;t stress and do it</strong>, it&#8217;s fine! We left Koh Chang at 7 AM and arrived at our hostel in Siem Reap at 5 PM<strong>. </strong>I can&#8217;t say it was a pleasant journey but it wasn&#8217;t that bad and<strong> it turned out to be a bit of fun.</strong> It&#8217;s sad neither the Thai nor Cambodian governments care about tourists being scammed as soon as they enter their countries. This shouldn&#8217;t stop you from enjoying what really is a beautiful country with beautiful people!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong>Accommodation</strong></h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for accommodation, we stayed at <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Velkommen Guesthouse</a>.</strong> It was cheap, nice (swimming pool!) and well located as it&#8217;s closer to Angkor Wat than most of the hostels. They provide free bikes so you can cycle to the city centre (10 minutes) or to Angkor Wat! 100% recommended it!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-215" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg" alt="crossing the cambodian border: safe and sound :)" width="467" height="831" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445.jpg 1166w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-169x300.jpg 169w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180331_092445-576x1024.jpg 576w" sizes="(max-width: 467px) 100vw, 467px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">Crossing the Cambodian border (and survive!)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-06-12 23:13:32 by W3 Total Cache
-->