<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>koh samui Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-samui/feed/?simply_static_page=47518" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-samui/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 11:07:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>koh samui Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/koh-samui/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rafag]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 03:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[12goasia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bangkok]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreamtrip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koh samui]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 options:</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348"><strong>Flight to Bangkok from Koh Samui</strong></a></h2>
<p>The most comfortable way but only for those travelling on a deep budget. Bangkok Airways runs this route many times during the day at around 130$ one way. The flight is 1hour 15 minutes and Bangkok Airways is spot on, including their tasty snack. Book here in <a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348">SkyScanner</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Bus</strong></a></h2>
<p>This option will take you to Bangkok in 12-13 hours depending on the starting port and the company. We have NOT done it but we&#8217;ve heard some opinions. It&#8217;s not <em>too</em> bad but keeps in mind you will be on a boat for a long time and then a long run in a bus will be waiting for you. Not much fun, especially on choppy days.</p>
<p>The price is around 1200฿-1400฿ (38-44$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Train</strong></a></h2>
<p>A bit more comfortable but very long, around 18 hours. A ferry will take you to the mainland and then by van, you will get to Suratthani train station. Then you need to take a train to Bangkok. The train goes from 18:37 to 06:30 so you can get some good sleep in the night.</p>
<p>The price goes from 2289฿ for a train first class ticket (72$) or 1758฿ for a second class ticket (55$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Flight</strong></a></h3>
<p>Our favourite, since it is good value on money, comfort and time. You could do the whole trip in around 6 hours depending on how long you need to wait for your flight. You&#8217;ll be taken from <strong>Na Thon </strong>port to mainland in a ferry run by <em>Seatran Ferry</em>. The ride is actually nice, safe boat and it has a bar where you can get some instant soups at a good price. After an hour and a half, you get to the mainland, where a van is waiting for you to take you to the airport. Once there you just need to take a flight to Bangkok.</p>
<p>There are very economics flights provided by Thai Smile (great) or Thai Lion (just ok). The price for the boat+van goes from 230฿ for the very early boats to 400฿, plus 30-40$ for the flight. In total, you will get spend around 40-50$, almost as cheap as the Ferry + Bus option but way more comfortable and fast. <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The last tip</strong>: make sure you find a proper way to get to the port. We used an app called NavigoApp (Uber/Grab style) because we were told it was way cheaper than normal taxis in Koh Samui. We paid 550฿ from Lamai Beach to Na Thon. However, some fellow travellers did the same trip using a regular taxi for 350฿. I think they just got lucky with the taxi driver, but overall our experience with NavigoApp was awful as the app barely work.</p>
<p>Happy travelling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-06-04 16:29:08 by W3 Total Cache
-->