<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Angkor Park Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/angkor-park/feed/?simply_static_page=60243" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/angkor-park/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:35:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Angkor Park Archives - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/tag/angkor-park/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Cycling Angkor Wat: How I almost killed my girlfriend</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cycling-around-angkor-wat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 06:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angkor Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angkor wat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siem reap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/?p=447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cycling around Angkor Wat was great until we realized what was ahead of us&#8230; After a long trip from Thailand, we had made it to Siem Reap (Cambodia) ready to enjoy of Angkor Wat or more correctly Angkor Park, a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Angkor is a 1000 years old city, a huge temple complex [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cycling-around-angkor-wat/">Cycling Angkor Wat: How I almost killed my girlfriend</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cycling around Angkor Wat was great until we realized what was ahead of us&#8230;</p>
<p>After a long trip from Thailand, we had made it to Siem Reap (Cambodia) ready to enjoy of Angkor Wat or more correctly Angkor Park, a UNESCO World Heritage Site.<strong> Angkor is a 1000 years old city, a huge temple complex and the largest religious monument in the world, as large as the size of London!</strong> Not so long ago, it was completely covered by the surrounding jungle and in fact, many temples are still hidden, waiting for the Cambodian government to gather some money to uncover them.</p>
<p>Angkor Wat was built in Angkor, the capital of the Khmer empire, one of the most powerful empires of the world between the 9th and 15th centuries. It was originally constructed as a Hindu temple, but it gradually transformed into a Buddhist temple towards the end of the 12th century. An interesting fact is that still today, it is unknown why and how the empire weakened, being 1431 the date for its collapse when the Siamese kingdom of Ayutthaya sacked the whole city.</p>
<p>The expectations were high and I was a bit afraid Angkor Park would disappoint us. Turns out there is nothing to worry about. Angkor Wat is a MUST for every true traveler. And if you&#8217;re a temple geek, you will simply love it.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-563 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg" alt="Rafa in Angkor Wat" width="392" height="588" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-200x300.jpg 200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /></p>
<h2><strong>How to get there?</strong></h2>
<p>Angkor Park is in Siem Reap, Cambodia. You can fly to Siem Reap, or <a href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/2018/05/07/how-to-survive-crossing-the-thai-cambodian-border/">cross the Thai-Cambodian border if you&#8217;re coming from Thailand like we did</a>. You could also do the same thing if you come from Vietnam.</p>
<h2><strong>How much is it?</strong></h2>
<p>Siem Reap is very cheap, costing a meal around 3$. Accommodation is also cheap, we stayed on <strong><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/kh/velkommen-boutique-villa.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1">Velkommen Guesthouse</a> </strong>and it was around 10$ each night. The hotel was top notch, great staff, very clean, provided bikes and it had a (small) swimming pool.</p>
<p>Angkor Park, however, is quite pricey. You have 3 options:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>1 day: 37$</strong>. Too short, you will barely have time to enjoy Angkor Wat and a few temples around, but that&#8217;s it.</li>
<li><strong>3 days: 62$</strong>. This is what we did. The third wasn&#8217;t necessary for us, but there is nothing you can do about it.</li>
<li><strong>7 days: 72$</strong>. Only if you&#8217;re REALLY a temples fan.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>How to move around</strong></h2>
<p>Most of the people hire a Tuk Tuk from the street or the hotel to visit the park. Other moves around by motorbikes, despite the rumors of this being illegal. And others, like us,<strong> decide cycling around Angkor Wat</strong> is the way to go. If you hire a Tuk Tuk from the street, make sure your driver speaks a bit of English as this will make a big difference in your visit. Also, make sure you negotiate the price as otherwise, they will rip you off. Hiring someone from the hotel should be a very good idea despite the commission too.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-542 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="3500" height="2800" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921.jpg 3500w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-300x240.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-768x614.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04921-1024x819.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3500px) 100vw, 3500px" /></p>
<h2><strong>Our experience</strong></h2>
<h3><em>First day: big circuit</em></h3>
<p>We wanted to be active and decided to use the bikes the hotel provided to us. Angkor is a really HOT place so you have to start the day very early and retire early. A very popular thing nowadays is to get to the park at <strong>5:30AM to see Angkor Wat at sunrise</strong>. We read this has become kind of a tourist trap as it gets really crowded and you barely see anything, so we decided to draw our own plan.</p>
<p>The alarm rang at 4:30AM. Equipped with our lanterns, we cycled to Angkor Park. 30 minutes later, we passed by Angkor Wat. Staying there was not appealing at all, it was so busy! That&#8217;s why we stuck to the plan and cycle a bit more. 10 minutes later we made it to Bayon, one of the biggest temples in the park. We were just in time for the sunrise and oh boy, it was well worth it. <strong>We had the temple just for ourselves, only to be shared with a dog and a monk that was having his early walk.</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-551 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg" alt="Angkor Wat sunrise" width="2200" height="1467" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1.jpg 2200w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04828-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2200px) 100vw, 2200px" /></p>
<p>From here, you can either do the small circuit or the big one. <strong>We decided to go for the big one and I have to be honest: we completely underestimated how exhausting cycling around Angkor Park can be.</strong> Preah Khan, Neak Pean, Ta Som are a few names of temples we visited.</p>
<p>Around 1 PM we were a bit templed out and decided to call it for the day. If you ask me, the way back home was fun and rewarding (we saw a family of monkeys on the road!) but if you ask Iga she will probably say different. She barely spoke to me for a few hours haha. To be fair, cycling 35 km under the sun wasn&#8217;t on my plans either.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-548 size-full" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg" alt="Temples" width="3000" height="2000" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3.jpg 3000w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-6-small-3-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3000px) 100vw, 3000px" /></p>
<p>After this, we headed to the city center to have lunch. Parallel to the Old Market, there is a street with plenty of options. We had lunch in one where the beer was ridiculously cheap, like 0.5$ or even less. That felt GOOD after so much cycling!</p>
<p>Time to come back to the hotel and chill by the pool! For dinner, we couldn&#8217;t bother to go to the city center again and ended up eating in a local restaurant nearby. We got Fish Amok and Khmer Red Curry, both typical Cambodian dishes. We didn&#8217;t love them but they were alright. Take your anti-mosquitoes with you for the night or you will regret it!</p>
<h3><em>Second day: small circuit</em></h3>
<p>Cycling around Angkor Wat for a second day would have cost me my relationship. So, we hired a TukTuk from our hotel. Our driver, called Dada, was such a nice guy and helped us to plan the day. The price was around 28$ + tip, which obviously is up to you. We are budget travelers but for what he offered and what we learned from him we were more than happy with the price.</p>
<p>We decided not to do the sunrise thing in Angkor Wat as we were very tired and wanted to get some sleep time. Also, from what we had seen the previous day it didn&#8217;t look worth it. In the end, we got to Angkor Wat at 6.30 AM and spent 2 hours walking around. The pictures say it all, it is indeed amazing!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-561 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg" alt="A monk in Angkor Wat" width="2734" height="1864" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2.jpg 2734w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-300x205.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-768x524.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/DSC04929-2-1024x698.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 2734px) 100vw, 2734px" /></p>
<p>After Angkor Wat, Dada took us to Banteay Samre, a temple quite far from the small/big circuits, deep in the countryside. It took 45 minutes to get there. The temple was very cool, but the ride in the Tuk Tuk was even better. We got to really see how Cambodians family live in the countryside (they live under 1$ per day) and the landscapes are BEAUTIFUL. We stopped along the way to learn how the palm oil is done and taste some sweets made out of it, very very tasty! Pure sugar straight to your blood.</p>
<p>After this, Dada took us back to our hotel to have lunch and a nap. He picked us up around 3 PM to see the rest of the small circuit. The highlight of the day was Ta Prohm, also called the &#8220;Tomb Raider&#8221; temple, as the movie was filmed here. In this temple, you really feel like you&#8217;re Angelina Jolie or Indiana Jones. It is truly amazing and I think we enjoyed it even more than Angkor Wat.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-541 size-full aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg" alt="Tomb Raider" width="1795" height="1346" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146.jpg 1795w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-300x225.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-768x576.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/GOPR3146-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1795px) 100vw, 1795px" /></p>
<p>To finish the day, Dada took us to enjoy the sunset to Phnom Bakheng, a viewpoint where it said you get amazing views. Unfortunately, they only allow 300 people up there so we couldn&#8217;t enjoy it. One thing I wish they changed it&#8217;s the fact they tell you this once you&#8217;ve reached the very top of the hill. So much for nothing! Anyway, we came back to Dada and asked him to take us to <strong>see the sunset at Angkor Wat</strong>. The sun doesn&#8217;t set there, but we had the chance to take beautiful pictures as it was less crowded than usual.</p>
<p>Just worth mentioning, we found many kids begging and selling stuff around Angkor Wat (and other temples), supervised by their parents in the distance. PLEASE don&#8217;t buy anything from them, these kids should be in school but if their parents see they can make a living out of them they will do it.</p>
<p>After this, Dada took us back to Siem Reap, where we had dinner in the city centre. We tried the best ice cream we have ever had: fried ice cream! It is hard to describe how it tastes but believe me, you won&#8217;t regret having it. There are many different flavours, we tried Oreo and Kinder Bueno, and both were simply amazing.</p>
<p>We had another half day in Siem Reap, but we were exhausted and a bit templed out. That&#8217;s why we decided to spend it chilling by the pool and getting ready to take the bus to Phnom Peng, the capital of Cambodia.</p>
<p>What about you? Have you already visited Angkor Wat? If not&#8230;does cycling around Angkor Wat something for you?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-540 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg" alt="Sunset in Angkor Wat" width="3300" height="2200" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small.jpg 3300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-300x200.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-768x512.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Angkor-Wat-small-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 3300px) 100vw, 3300px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Did you like it? Share it!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-761 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png" alt="Cycling around Angkor Wat" width="647" height="364" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001.png 560w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/20180807_201636_0001-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 647px) 100vw, 647px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/cycling-around-angkor-wat/">Cycling Angkor Wat: How I almost killed my girlfriend</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-06-06 21:18:45 by W3 Total Cache
-->