<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Thailand - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<atom:link href="http://localhost/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/thailand/feed/?simply_static_page=115147" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/thailand/</link>
	<description>Iga and Rafa. Travellers couple venturing around the world. Sharing our stories and tips for authentic experience seekers. The best plan is to say yes to new adventures!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 23:02:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/cropped-cropped-copy-of-copy-of-star-onboarding-title-page-e1529730874184-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Thailand - It feels good to be lost</title>
	<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/category/thailand/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Note: This post was last updated on June 2023 to include the most current information and recommendations. If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note</strong>: This post was last updated on <strong>June 2023</strong> to include the most current information and recommendations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re planning a trip to Thailand, Koh Chang should be on your list. In this guide, we&#8217;ll explore the best things to do in Koh Chang, a hidden gem in Trat&#8217;s province, southeast of Thailand. Despite fierce competition, there are compelling reasons to believe that Koh Chang is one of the best islands in Thailand.</p>
<h2><strong>Getting to Koh Chang</strong></h2>
<p>Getting to Koh Chang might be a bit tricky as there&#8217;s no airport on the island. You can either fly to Trat&#8217;s airport from Bangkok and then take a taxi to Ao Thammachat&#8217;s port, where you can reach Koh Chang by sea in 30 minutes. Alternatively, you can take a bus from Ekkamai&#8217;s bus station in Bangkok, which takes around six hours (but is very comfortable!), and then catch a boat.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;re on the island, you can get around by taxi or by renting a motorbike. <strong>Exploring Koh Chang on a motorbike is one of our favorite memories from our trips around the world</strong>. It&#8217;s the best and cheapest option if you know how to drive.</p>
<p>Now, let&#8217;s dive into the best things to do in Koh Chang.</p>
<h2><strong>What to do</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>Klong Koi Beach</strong></h4>
<p>This beach is a paradise. The sand is amazing, and the water is surprisingly warm. On your way, visit Bang Bao Pier, where you can have a smoothie and do some shopping in the shops on the pier.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-184 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg" alt="koh chang " width="640" height="776" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-845x1024.jpg 845w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-248x300.jpg 248w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-768x931.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1267x1536.jpg 1267w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-xx1-e1582292336841-1690x2048.jpg 1690w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<h4><strong>Lonely Beach</strong></h4>
<p>While the beach in Lonely Beach is nothing special, the area is great for enjoying food or having some drinks. The atmosphere is very chilled during the day, although it can get a bit lively at night with some parties going on. Lonely Beach is also a great spot to enjoy sunrises. We enjoyed an awesome one at <a href="https://www.agoda.com/es-es/warapura-resort/hotel/koh-chang-th.html?finalPriceView=2&amp;isShowMobileAppPrice=false&amp;cid=1763310&amp;numberOfBedrooms=&amp;familyMode=false&amp;adults=2&amp;children=0&amp;rooms=1&amp;maxRooms=0&amp;checkIn=2023-06-12&amp;isCalendarCallout=false&amp;childAges=&amp;numberOfGuest=0&amp;missingChildAges=false&amp;travellerType=-1&amp;showReviewSubmissionEntry=false&amp;currencyCode=EUR&amp;isFreeOccSearch=false&amp;tag=3ca4e5ca-12bf-3f82-a5b3-51dd334b432a&amp;isCityHaveAsq=false&amp;los=1&amp;searchrequestid=d3196397-4a4e-4057-a418-7c2e442572b1">Warapura Resort</a>, which has happy hours in the early evening, making it the perfect spot to see the sunset.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-171 aligncenter" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang-sunset-e1582292527691.jpg" alt="koh chang sunset" width="800" height="600" /></p>
<h4>Best Beaches in Koh Chang: White Sand, Khlong Prao, and Kai Bae</h4>
<p>These three beaches are some of the best places to visit in Koh Chang. White Sand Beach is the most popular and busiest beach on the island. It&#8217;s a great place to relax, swim, and enjoy the sun. There are plenty of restaurants and bars nearby, making it a lively place to spend the day.</p>
<p>Khlong Prao Beach is a bit quieter but equally beautiful. It&#8217;s a long, sandy beach that&#8217;s perfect for long walks and sunbathing. The beach is lined with coconut trees, adding to its tropical charm. There are also several resorts and restaurants nearby.</p>
<p>Kai Bae Beach is a hidden gem. It&#8217;s less crowded than the other two beaches, making it a great place to relax and enjoy the tranquility. The beach is surrounded by lush greenery, creating a serene and peaceful atmosphere.</p>
<h4>Exploring Khlong Phlu Waterfall: A Must-Do in Koh Chang</h4>
<p>If you get tired of beaches, you can go to Khlong Phlu, where you can have a nice short trek and enjoy sunbathing by a waterfall. You can dive in if you don&#8217;t mind the company of the small-medium fish!</p>
<p>Remember to wear sturdy shoes for the hike and bring some insect repellent to protect yourself from mosquitoes. There&#8217;s a small entrance fee to the national park, but it&#8217;s well worth it for the chance to see this beautiful waterfall.</p>
<h2>Accommodation</h2>
<h4><strong>Budget option: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.es.html">Little Eden Bungalows</a></strong></h4>
<p>For budget travelers, Little Eden Bungalows is a great option. Located in Lonely Beach, there are about 10 small bungalows. They also rent motorbikes for a good price (300 bahts).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.booking.com/hotel/th/little-eden-bungalows.html?aid=1530608&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=1"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-187 size-large" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg" alt="little eden" width="640" height="563" srcset="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1024x900.jpg 1024w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-300x264.jpg 300w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-768x675.jpg 768w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-1536x1349.jpg 1536w, https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-chang15-e1582293916267-2048x1799.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>Comfort option</strong>: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.es.html">Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort</a></h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a bit more comfort, Santhiya Tree Koh Chang Resort is an excellent choice. With its excellent location, amazing pool, live music, delicious breakfast, and great sunsets, it&#8217;s an outstanding resort.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/santhiya.en.html?aid=1593090&amp;no_rooms=1&amp;group_adults=2"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="size-full aligncenter" src="https://q-cf.bstatic.com/images/hotel/max1280x900/162/162915342.jpg" width="1280" height="853" /></a></p>
<h2><strong>Embrace the Adventure</strong></h2>
<p>Remember, Koh Chang is one of those places where you don’t really need to worry about what to do. Just ride a motorbike and GET LOST. You can also visit Koh Mak and Koh Kut, the other islands in the archipelago. We&#8217;ve heard great things about them, but they are a bit far, so if you go, make sure you get some accommodation to spend the night and make the most of them.</p>
<p><em>You may also find interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/crossing-the-cambodian-border/">How to survive crossing Thai-Cambodian border</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/" rel="bookmark" data-wplink-url-error="true">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a></em></li>
<li class="news-title"><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/" rel="bookmark">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Enjoyed the article? We provide our content free and without the use of affiliates, this is how you know we&#8217;re authentic. If you&#8217;d like to support us to continue doing this, consider buying us a coffee!<script src="https://cdnjs.buymeacoffee.com/1.0.0/button.prod.min.js" type="text/javascript" data-name="bmc-button" data-slug="itfeelsgoodtobelost" data-color="#13d5d8" data-emoji="" data-font="Cookie" data-text="Buy me a coffee" data-outline-color="#000000" data-font-color="#000000" data-coffee-color="#FFDD00"></script></em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/best-things-to-do-in-koh-chang/">Best Things to Do in Koh Chang: Discover Thailand&#8217;s Hidden Gem</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 13:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Updated in 2023: This post has been updated to ensure it contains the most accurate and comprehensive guide for exploring Koh Samet. Enjoy planning your adventure! Embarking on an adventure exploring Koh Samet, a lovely island nestled in the Gulf of Thailand, is a perfect escape from the bustling city of Bangkok. This comprehensive travel [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/">Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i><strong>U</strong><b>pdated in 2023</b>: This post has been updated to ensure it contains the most accurate and comprehensive guide for exploring Koh Samet. Enjoy planning your adventure!</i></p>
<p>Embarking on an adventure exploring Koh Samet, a lovely island nestled in the Gulf of Thailand, is a perfect escape from the bustling city of Bangkok. This comprehensive travel guide will help you navigate through the island&#8217;s pristine beaches, amazing sunsets, and vibrant nightlife. Koh Samet is still a hidden gem, so make sure you explore this paradise before it becomes another crowded island!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">If you are like us and made the mistake to spend some days in Pattaya you&#8217;ll find exploring Koh Samet a refreshing experience.<span id="more-68"></span></p>
<h3><strong>How to get there?</strong></h3>
<p>We went to Koh Samet from Pattaya. If you&#8217;re going from Bangkok, I&#8217;d expect there are buses from Ekkamai bus station to Ban Phe port. Worst scenario, you could easily go to Pattaya and then go to Ban Phe. This is how we did it from Pattaya:</p>
<ol>
<li>Go to this <strong style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );"><a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Praew+Souvenir+@Tesco+Lotus+Central+Pattaya/@12.9337661,100.9025029,18z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x3102be1c9a4d3ec5:0xade9af5b32c85c66!2sPattaya+Bus+station!8m2!3d12.9499477!4d100.9033208!3m4!1s0x310295f03b6ec8e3:0x26063f5fe5264481!8m2!3d12.9337639!4d100.9034285">location</a></strong>. In front of the Tesco Lotus, there is a <b style="color: var( --e-global-color-text );">small travel office that organizes trips by van.</b></li>
<li>Tell them you want to go to <strong>Ban-Phe port</strong> to then go to Koh Samet<b>.</b> The trip takes an hour and it costs 300 bahts (2 people).</li>
<li>Once in the port, walk to the ticket office. There are slow and fast boats. We took a fast boat, which after haggling a bit, cost us 250 bahts (2 people).</li>
<li>A short 15-minute ride later, you&#8217;ll arrive at Koh Samet. A coast guard will approach you to collect the national park fee, which is 200 baht. Rest assured, exploring Koh Samet is worth every penny!</li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180318_144359-e1570995593904.jpg" alt="Ban Phe port" width="3120" height="2085" /></p>
<h3><strong>How to move around</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">The island is fairly small, but you&#8217;ll need transport to move around. Options are:</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hopping in big taxis that move around the island all day.</strong> The price depends on where you&#8217;re going but keep in mind they&#8217;re generally pricey.</li>
<li><strong>Rent a bike and cycle around!</strong> Ecological and cheap.</li>
<li style="text-align: left;"><strong>Our favorite: hire a motorbike </strong>(250 bahts per day). Only for those who know how to drive. If you&#8217;re a beginner, you should be fine as it is quite easy to drive in Koh Samet. Drive safely!</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>A few things to convince you why exploring Koh Samet is worth it</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Hat Sai Kaew Beach</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">The most popular beach. During the day expect a lot of people, towels, activities like snorkeling and so on.  In the night the atmosphere is stunning: nice restaurants, fire shows, relaxed parties, locals hanging out&#8230;</p>
<h3><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" style="font-size: 16px;" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/koh-samet-bar.png" alt="Naga Bar" width="655" height="471" /></h3>
<figure id="attachment_1153" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1153" style="width: 664px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/koh-samet-bar2.png" alt="Naga Bar Koh Samet" width="664" height="475" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1153" class="wp-caption-text">Naga Bar offers chilled atmosphere during the day and great party vibes at night</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Ao Prao beach</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Simply</strong> <strong>paradise</strong>. Surrounded by resorts, but don&#8217;t let this put you off. The water is a stunning shade of blue and crystal clear, and the sand couldn&#8217;t be any whiter. We&#8217;ve visited quite a few beaches, and this is one of our favorites. Plus, we got to witness one of the most beautiful sunsets we&#8217;ve ever seen. Pictures simply don&#8217;t do it justice—you&#8217;ll have to go and see it for yourself!</p>
<figure id="attachment_84" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-84" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet2-1024x683.jpg" alt="Koh Samet is worth a visit" width="690" height="460" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-84" class="wp-caption-text">This sunset alone shows Koh Samet is worth a visit</figcaption></figure>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.files.wordpress.com/2018/05/koh-samet-beach-day.jpg" alt="koh samet beach" width="4799" height="2887" /></p>
<h3>Wat Koh Samet</h3>
<p>Buddism is an important part of the local culture, so if you want to experience that, the temple complex in the middle of the village called Wat Koh Samet is worth a visit. <strong>After climbing a few stars, you will find the famous big Buddha statue there. </strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_93" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-93" style="width: 449px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet61-e1570995284982.jpg" alt="Koh Samet Wat" width="449" height="589" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-93" class="wp-caption-text">Make sure to stop on your way to visit the Big Buddha in Koh Samet Wat</figcaption></figure>
<p>If you are a morning person <strong>you may be lucky to see monks walking down the streets and receiving alms</strong>, as the practice of offering food is called. Mothers have been cooking food for monks and giving alms since the dawn of Buddhism over 2,500 years ago!</p>
<figure id="attachment_92" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-92" style="width: 3114px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/img_20180318_112606.jpg" alt="Monks in the morning" width="3114" height="2715" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-92" class="wp-caption-text">Monks receiving alms in the morning</figcaption></figure>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/koh-samet-2-e1570995952859.jpg" alt="Mrrrau" width="440" height="549" /></p>
<h2><strong>Accommodation</strong></h2>
<h4><strong>Budget option: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/stay-samed">Stay Samet</a></strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: left;">Looking for a budget-friendly accommodation option while exploring Koh Samet? Consider Stay Samet. They offer both shared and private rooms that are clean and comfortable. The on-site restaurant serves a variety of healthy and delicious food. The reception staff is friendly and always ready to assist with anything. Plus, the location is excellent, with many shops and restaurants nearby.</p>
<h4><strong>Comfort option</strong>: <a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/th/samed-villa-resort">Samed Villa Resort</a></h4>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a more luxurious stay while exploring Koh Samet, consider Samed Villa Resort. This outstanding resort is located right in front of Ao Phai Beach, providing direct access to the beach. You can enjoy the best sunsets right from the resort! The rooms are stylish and clean, and don&#8217;t forget to indulge in their massage service!</p>
<h2>How to come back to Bangkok?</h2>
<p>All good comes to an end. Head to the pier and hop on the first departing boat to come back to the mainland<b>.</b> There are boats departing every hour. The slow one is 50 bahts and takes about an hour.</p>
<p><strong>There are buses heading to Bangkok </strong>at the bus station next to the pier<b>. </b>The price is 150 baths and the drop-off point is Ekkamai Bus Station.</p>
<p>To sum it up, exploring Koh Samet is an adventure worth undertaking, and we hope you enjoy it as much as we did</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/20180526_205828_0001.png" alt="Hidden gems of Thailand" width="560" height="315" /></p>
<p><em>You may also find it interesting&#8230;</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/why-koh-chang-is-the-best-island-in-thailand/">Why Koh Chang is the best island in Thailand</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://itfeelsgoodtobelost.com/3-week-vietnam-itinerary/">3 week Vietnam itinerary from north to south</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Enjoyed the article? We provide our content free and without the use of affiliates, this is how you know we&#8217;re authentic. If you&#8217;d like to support us to continue doing this, consider buying us a coffee!<script src="https://cdnjs.buymeacoffee.com/1.0.0/button.prod.min.js" type="text/javascript" data-name="bmc-button" data-slug="itfeelsgoodtobelost" data-color="#13d5d8" data-emoji="" data-font="Cookie" data-text="Buy me a coffee" data-outline-color="#000000" data-font-color="#000000" data-coffee-color="#FFDD00"></script></em></p>


<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/exploring-koh-samet-travel-guide/">Exploring Koh Samet: A Comprehensive Travel Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</title>
		<link>https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rafa Garcia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 03:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Thailand]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://itfeelsgoodtobelost.wordpress.com/?p=38</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this you&#8217;re probably planning your trip around Thailand and more specifically to beautiful Koh Samui. On this post, we explain how to get to Bangkok from Koh Samui. Also, if you are interested in the other way around, Koh Samui to Bangkok, the same rules and options apply. These are the 4 options:</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348"><strong>Flight to Bangkok from Koh Samui</strong></a></h2>
<p>The most comfortable way but only for those travelling on a deep budget. Bangkok Airways runs this route many times during the day at around 130$ one way. The flight is 1hour 15 minutes and Bangkok Airways is spot on, including their tasty snack. Book here in <a href="http://www.tkqlhce.com/click-8801912-10639348">SkyScanner</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Bus</strong></a></h2>
<p>This option will take you to Bangkok in 12-13 hours depending on the starting port and the company. We have NOT done it but we&#8217;ve heard some opinions. It&#8217;s not <em>too</em> bad but keeps in mind you will be on a boat for a long time and then a long run in a bus will be waiting for you. Not much fun, especially on choppy days.</p>
<p>The price is around 1200฿-1400฿ (38-44$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Train</strong></a></h2>
<p>A bit more comfortable but very long, around 18 hours. A ferry will take you to the mainland and then by van, you will get to Suratthani train station. Then you need to take a train to Bangkok. The train goes from 18:37 to 06:30 so you can get some good sleep in the night.</p>
<p>The price goes from 2289฿ for a train first class ticket (72$) or 1758฿ for a second class ticket (55$). <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Ferry + Van + Flight</strong></a></h3>
<p>Our favourite, since it is good value on money, comfort and time. You could do the whole trip in around 6 hours depending on how long you need to wait for your flight. You&#8217;ll be taken from <strong>Na Thon </strong>port to mainland in a ferry run by <em>Seatran Ferry</em>. The ride is actually nice, safe boat and it has a bar where you can get some instant soups at a good price. After an hour and a half, you get to the mainland, where a van is waiting for you to take you to the airport. Once there you just need to take a flight to Bangkok.</p>
<p>There are very economics flights provided by Thai Smile (great) or Thai Lion (just ok). The price for the boat+van goes from 230฿ for the very early boats to 400฿, plus 30-40$ for the flight. In total, you will get spend around 40-50$, almost as cheap as the Ferry + Bus option but way more comfortable and fast. <a href="https://12go.asia/en/travel/koh-samui/bangkok/?z=1511837"><strong>Book here</strong></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>The last tip</strong>: make sure you find a proper way to get to the port. We used an app called NavigoApp (Uber/Grab style) because we were told it was way cheaper than normal taxis in Koh Samui. We paid 550฿ from Lamai Beach to Na Thon. However, some fellow travellers did the same trip using a regular taxi for 350฿. I think they just got lucky with the taxi driver, but overall our experience with NavigoApp was awful as the app barely work.</p>
<p>Happy travelling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost/bangkok-from-koh-samui/">Bangkok from Koh Samui: the easy way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://rafagf.github.io/itfeelsgoodtobelost">It feels good to be lost</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced (Requested URI contains query) 

Served from: localhost @ 2023-07-29 23:33:52 by W3 Total Cache
-->